補充翻譯 校對: 尋找自己的貓
There he is. There's the stallion. That's War Winds.
就是那匹馬 它是匹種馬 名叫"戰風"
Beautiful.
真漂亮
That's my daughter riding him. Leslie.
騎著它的是 我女兒萊斯莉
Leslie's my daughter. She's riding him.
騎著那匹馬的 是我女兒萊斯莉
Doctor, that sure is a beautiful animal.
醫生 這匹馬真是漂亮極了
Yes. Well, we'll get to the horses first thing in the morning.
明天早上我們再去看馬
Right now you're coming up to the house and get ready for dinner.
現在先到我 家裏去用晚餐
So you're from Nevada, Mr. Beckwith?
貝克維斯先生 你來自內華達?
Texas, Mama.
是德州 媽媽
Oh, yes. Texas, Mr. Beckwith? Yes, ma'am, Texas.
你是來自德州 貝克維斯先生?
- Benedict's the name. - Oh, yes.
是的 夫人 我叫本尼迪特
- Oh, you're here about the horses, aren't you? - Yes, ma'am.
- 你是來買馬的 對嗎? - 是的 夫人
I came here to buy your stallion, War Winds.
我想買那匹種馬"戰風"
That is, if your daughter don't mind too much.
如果你女兒不介意的話
In all likelihood, our Leslie will be leaving us soon in any case.
萊斯莉很可能就要走了
Sir David is with the embassy in Washington...
戴維和大使在華盛頓
...and he's being called back to England.
他被召回英格蘭來了
Will she like it there, do you think?
你認為她會喜歡那裏嗎?
- She's going to marry him? - Well...
- 她要嫁給他? - 呃...
Mother.
媽媽!
Let me sell Mr. Benedict War Winds.
我會把"戰風" 賣給本尼迪特先生的
I can tell you all his bad points.
我來告訴你它所有的缺點
For one thing, he eats too much. Doesn't he, Papa?
首先 它吃得很多 對嗎 爸爸?
But you see, it's either War Winds or me. Something has to go.
不管是"戰風"還是我 都有一個要離開這裏
Now, Leslie, you know very well that horse is just too spirited for any woman to ride.
對於女人來說 那匹馬太剛烈了
I know, Miss Leslie, that your horse is gonna miss you...
你的馬會想念你的
...and all this green country...
還有這個美麗的莊園
...but I'll make him feel right at home in Texas.
可是… 在德州我也會讓它幸福的
Isn't Texas green, Mr. Benedict?
德州綠化好嗎 本尼迪特先生?
Well, no, ma'am. Not altogether.
不 夫人 並非綠化都很好
You must tell us about Texas, Mr. Benedict.
跟我們說說德州吧
Well, ma'am, it's not that easy. Um...
這可說來話長
It's different than any other state...
它和別的州
...I think.
都不一樣
At least that's what we think. But it's almost a different country.
至少我們是這樣覺得的 這是完全不同的一個地方
Hmm, from an Englishman's point of view...
從英國人的角度來說
...the mere size of it takes your breath away.
他們一向看重莊園的面積
It's big, all right.
是的 那裏確實很大
And how large are your ranches?
你的牧場有多大?
Almost every size. Large, small.
大小都有
Mr. Benedict's Reata is one of the largest of them all.
"利塔"是它們中最大的一個
Oh, really?
真的嗎?
Well, just how large is that?
那它有多大?
Oh, it's one of the biggest.
是最大的牧場之一
Hmm. - How big is that?
它到底有多大?
Well, there's one or two others as big, I suppose, up where we come from.
是其它牧場的一到兩倍 從我們來的那地方…
One or two others a bit larger down on the coastal plains.
相當於幾個 較大的海岸草原
Heh. But come, now, Mr. Benedict, can't you be more specific?
你能說得具體一點嗎?
Well, what's the size of your place? Fifty thousand, 20,000 acres?
你的牧場到底有多大? 5萬畝 2萬畝?
Around a half a million.
五十多萬畝
Five hundred and ninety-five thousand acres, to be exact.
具體應該是59.5萬畝
Ha, ha. I'd call that quite a parcel.
那真是夠大的!
How many acres did you say, Mr. Benedict?
你說的是多少畝 本尼迪特先生?
He said 595,000 acres, Mama.
他說的是59.5萬畝
And you should see the greedy look on your face.
你的兩眼都放光了 媽媽
Witness excused.
恕我冒昧
Won't you join us at the Hunt Ball, Mr. Benedict? I'm sure you'll enjoy it.
本尼迪特先生 一起來參加我們的舞會吧? 你一定會喜歡的
Oh, no, thank you anyhow, Miss Leslie.
不了 謝謝你 萊斯莉小姐
- I'm afraid I'd look good there in this outfit.   Ha, ha.
恐怕我的 這身衣服不大適合
I like your country.
我喜歡你們的莊園
Why don't you stay on a while, really see something of it?
那為何不多呆一會兒 仔細再看看這裏?
Roundup time in my country. Big spring roundup.
我莊園的獸群開始遷移了 春天大遷移
Your country?
你的莊園?
Reata.
"利塔"
Your country, my country. Jordan, you make us sound so far apart.
你的莊園 我的莊園 這樣說可把我們距離拉遠了
Maybe...
或許吧
...you could come out and see it...
你該去那裏看看
...when you get a chance.
如果你有機會的話
- Leslie - Leslie, dear.
- 萊斯莉 -萊斯莉,親愛的
Miss Leslie. Leslie?
萊斯莉小姐
I guess I'll be off real early in the morning, so...
明天一大早我就要離開了 所以…
...goodbye.
再見
I'm really awfully glad you came.
很高興見到你
And I'm not going to say goodbye to you here in the moonlight.
在這美好的月夜 我是不會和你說再見的
It would just be too touching. Good night.
這樣太傷感了 晚安!
Texas.
"德州"
Are you in love with him?
你愛上他了?
Yes, I think so.
我想是的
Now, will you do me a favor and run along to bed?
睡覺去吧 就算幫我個忙好嗎?
- Leslie? - Good night.
-萊斯莉? -晚安
If you're not going to marry David Karfrey...
如果你不和 戴維結婚的話…
...will you give him to me?
可以把他讓給我嗎?
Yes. Now, good night.
好的!晚安
As far as I'm concerned, Dr. Lynnton, it's a deal.
我所關心的是 這是筆交易
- Ten thousand dollars is a lot of money. - He sure is a lot of horse.
- 一萬美金可是個大數目 - 也可以買很多匹馬
Let's have some breakfast and get going.
我們用完早餐後再繼續吧
Hello.
你好
- Why, Leslie. - Good morning.
- 萊斯莉! - 早上好
Good morning.
早上好
Well, you don't look as if you've been dancing all night, Miss Leslie.
你似乎並沒有整晚跳舞 萊斯莉小姐
I came home at a quarter to 11.
我昨晚10:45回家
And I read about Texas until 5 this morning.
然後看那本"德州" 看到早上五點
Oh, Leslie, let the poor boy eat his breakfast in peace.
先讓他先用完早餐再說
Ma'am, that takes a heap of reading, Texas does.
那本"德州"裏面 有很多內容
We really stole Texas, didn't we, Mr. Benedict?
德州是被我們偷來的 對嗎?
I mean, away from Mexico.
我是指 從墨西哥偷來的
You're catching me a bit early to start joking.
一大早你就來 跟我開這種玩笑
But I'm not joking,Jordan.
我沒在說笑 喬丹
It's all there in the history books, isn't it?
曆史書上都是這麼說的
This man, Mr. Austin, came down with about 300 families, it says.
書上說 奧斯丁和 他的三百個家人先到了那裏
The next thing you know, they're up and claiming it from Mexico.
接著 他們就把 它從墨西哥奪來了
But, Leslie...
等下 萊斯莉
Why, I never heard anything as ignorant...
我從不相信一些 無知東方人所說的話
Oh, please, Jordan.
行了 喬丹
I'm speaking impersonally, about history.
我只是在客觀地 談論曆史而已
You all think that the glory happened here in the East...
你們都認為 這一榮譽只在東部…
- ...with Valley Forge and Bunker Hill. Oh, Jordan...
威利.弗吉和 本克.希爾也是如此!
Do you know about San Jacinto? Have you heard about the Alamo?
你聽說過聖.賈辛托 和阿拉莫嗎?
Well, certainly.
當然
I read about them all last night.
昨晚我都看過他們的曆史
I didn't mean to be impolite. But it's so new to me.
我並非有意無禮 但這些對於我實在太新奇了
I just mean... It's just all so new.
我是說 所有一切 都是那麼的新奇…
And so fascinating.
那麼的吸引人!
Leslie, you mustn't talk that way to a Texan. They feel very strongly about their state.
你不能這樣跟德州人說話 他們對德州都有著很強烈情感
He shouldn't take it so hard.
他也不必這麼認真
Jordan, you would think somebody had spoiled you terribly.
喬丹 你一定是受慣了 別人的體貼和寵愛
Your wife or something.
你妻子或者別的人
I haven't any wife. I live with my sister.
我沒有妻子 我和姐姐一起生活
Why aren't you married, Jordan?
你為何沒結婚呢?
Leslie, first you attack a man's country, and now you try to pry into his family life.
你剛剛冒犯了人家 現在又打聽別人的私生活
Thank you, doctor.
謝謝你 醫生
- Good morning. - Good morning.
-早上好 -早上好
- Good morning, Lacey. - Good morning, Papa.
-早上好 蕾茜 -早上好 爸爸
How are we doing?
怎麼樣?
We'll have to be getting along soon, Jordan, if you're going to make your train.
我們得快點了 否則就要錯過火車了
- Well, good morning, everybody. - Good morning, Nancy.
-早上好 各位 -早上好 南茜
Good morning, dear. Good morning, Mr. Benedict.
早上好 親愛的 早上好 本尼迪特先生
Oh, isn't it a beautiful morning?
今天天氣真好啊!
Leslie, if Mr. Benedict has finished his breakfast...
萊斯莉 一會兒本尼迪特先生 吃完早餐…
...why don't you show him the stables?
為何不帶他到 馬棚去參觀一下?
We have just quarreled in a polite way about Texas.
我們剛爭論完德州的曆史
- There's no use trying to pawn me off on him. - Oh.
即使把我典當給他 恐怕也無濟於事了
And anyway, Mother, Mr. Benedict is probably engaged to marry...
不過 媽媽… 他或許已經和他附近
...the daughter at the adjoining ranch...
大牧場主的女兒訂婚了
...who, though beautiful, is comparatively poor...
她也很漂亮 只不過比不上他有錢而已
...and only has 200,000 acres and half a million cows.
她的牧場只有二十萬畝 和五十萬頭牛而已
Is she, um, pretty?
她漂亮嗎?
Ma'am?
女士
We must hurry.
我們得趕緊上路了
Mr. Benedict and I will have to be leaving now.
本尼迪特先生現在得走了
Goodbye, everybody.
再見 所有人
Benedict.
本尼迪特
Who, may I ask, is the lucky young lady that you're going to marry?
我可以問一下 那個有那麼多牛的 幸運小姐…
With all those cows.
是哪一位啊?
Benedict.
本尼迪特
I'll get the car.
我去把車開來
- Funny thing, ma'am. - Yes?
太滑稽了 夫人
- My neighbor is a girl. - Oh?
我的鄰居只是個女孩
- Vashti Hake. - Hmm.
她叫瓦斯塔.海克
Maybe there was some talk of my marrying her, but I'm not.
人們也曾說過類似的話 但我是不會娶她的
Come along, Benedict, if you want to catch that train.
快點 不然就趕不上火車了
Oh. It all sounds so romantic.
聽起來真浪漫!
Come along, David.
戴維
You're for me.
陪陪我吧
What's that, a wolf?
那是什麼 狼嗎?
No, honey.
不 親愛的
Just a little old coyote.
只是只小山狗而已
Don't you think you've done enough sightseeing for a while?
還沒看夠外面的風景嗎?
Tell me as soon as we're in Texas.
到德州後好好跟我說說
That's Texas you been looking at, honey.
你剛才看的就是德州
For the last eight hours.
八小時前就到德州了
I don't know how other brides feel on their honeymoon, Mr. Benedict, sir...
我不知道其他 新娘的蜜月之旅感受如何
...but I'm having a lovely time.
但我真的很開心
You can't say it's been dull, honey.
現在還不會覺得乏味
That is, um, so far, anyway.
至少目前是這樣
Wake up, honey. We're here, honey.
醒醒 親愛的 我們到了
We're where?
到哪兒了?
Hello.
你好
Good morning.
早上好
Is that Texas?
這裏就是德州?
It's Benedict, honey. It's where we ship from.
這是本尼迪特牧場 也就是我們要去的地方
These people never learn.
這些人從來都學不聰明!
I'm Mrs. Benedict.
我是本尼迪特太太
That means "Welcome the newlyweds." Gracias, Angel.
那是指"歡迎歸來 新婚夫婦"  謝謝 安吉爾
Oh. Gracias. Gracias, gracias.
噢 謝謝
Let's go, Leslie.
走吧 萊斯莉
And what is your name?
你叫什麼名字?
Angel. Angel Obregon.
安吉爾 安吉爾 奧夫雷貢
Oh, my, that's a beautiful name. Gracias, Angel Obregon.
這名字真好聽
Come on, Leslie, it's 50 miles to coffee.
好了 還有五十公裏的路要走呢
This is it, honey. This is your home.
到了 親愛的 這就是你的家
But it's huge.
但是它太大了!
I thought it was a ranch house.
我還以為是一間平房而已
My old man built it to show the cotton crowd...
這房子是我的祖先建的
...that cattlemen were just as high-powered as they were.
讓那些柔弱的人 看看我們有多能幹
Why, it's enormous, just for two of us.
就我們倆住似乎太大了
Luz lives here with me.
盧斯和我一起住
With us.
和我們一起住
She's run the house ever since Ma passed on.
媽媽去世後就由她照看這房子
Some say she even runs the ranch.
也可以說由她照看這個牧場
Gracias. Gracias.
謝謝
Take it easy, Leslie.
別緊張 萊斯莉
- What are your names? Lupe.
你們叫什麼名字?
Petra, senora. - Lupe Petra
佩特拉 女士 -盧佩 佩特拉
- Gracias, Lupe. Gracias, Petra. Gracias, senora.
- 謝謝 盧佩 謝謝 佩特拉 -謝謝 女士
Leslie.
萊斯莉
- You can't behave like that. - What do you mean, behave?
- 你這樣做可不行 - 什麼意思?
Down here, making a fuss over those people.
對他們無需講究那麼多禮節
You're a Texan now.
你現在是個德州人了
Well, is that a state of mind?
那也是一種思想嗎?
I'm still myself.
我還是我自己
You're my wife, honey.
你是我妻子 親愛的
You're a Benedict.
你是本尼迪特夫人
I still have a mind of my own.
我有自己的想法.
Elsewhere, being gracious is acceptable.
無論到哪兒 禮貌待人是很重要的
We're gracious, but...
我們是要禮貌待人 但是…
Fine thing, standing here quarreling...
好了… 別在這裏爭論
...the rice still in our hair.
這些雞毛蒜皮的小事了!
Oh, it's so nice and cool.
感覺真是太棒了!
Luz. Heh.
盧斯 嘿
I thought somebody was hurt.
我還以為有人受傷了
We, uh, didn't know you was there.
我們不知道你在那裏
Well, we're home. We're here.
終於到家了
Been looking for you for weeks.
我找了你幾個星期了
We weren't expected to be back sooner, were we?
我們是不是回來晚了?
Well, with all this spring work to be done. Roundup.
春天有很多活兒要做 比如牲畜的遷移…
I didn't figure Bick would stay away.
我沒想到畢克會外出
Well, if I miss roundup every time I have a honeymoon...
幸好還有這次蜜月
- ...I wouldn't be missing much, would I? Ha, ha.
所以我並沒有錯過太多 對嗎?
I thought I fired him off this place.
我還以為已經把他解雇了呢
Hey, Jett.
嘿 傑特
Where do you think you're going with my automobile?
你要開著我的車到哪兒去?
Just hold on.
別緊張
Don't go taking off on me.
別責怪我
That old truck broke down again. Just simmer down.
那輛老掉牙的卡車又壞了
You want me going down the road?
你想讓我走人是嗎?
That's exactly what I was gonna do.
我也正求之不得
But she said to me, "You stay on here and do your work."
但她說"你留下來 幹完自己的活兒吧"
Next time I tell you to get, you get.
下回我要你來的時候 你才可以來!
Jordan and Jett are everlasting jangling about something. Excuse me.
畢克和傑特老是這樣斗嘴
Tell Madama. She's the one that told it to me.
可是瑪塔瑪讓我留下來的
That's right.
沒錯
With you away, we needed the help.
你一走 我們這裏人手就不夠了
You know how scared they are of her. They're scared to death of her.
大家都很害怕她
You know that.
這你也知道的
Every one of them except me and you.
我和你除外
You just tend to your work. - Tell me who's the boss around here.
去做你自己的活兒去吧 告訴我 誰才是這裏的主人…
I'll be glad to do anything they want me to do. Just tell me who's the boss and, uh...
我會很樂意為你做一切事情的 你只需告訴我誰是這兒的主人
Jett, this is Bick's new wife.
這是畢克的妻子
Leslie, this boy here is Jett Rink.
萊斯莉 他叫傑特.林克
- Hello. Works for us.
-你好 -他為我們工作的
You'd better get going, Jett. Get that truck fixed.
你最好趕緊走 傑特 去把那輛卡車修好
Ain't nobody king in this country.
這個莊園裏 沒人可以自稱國王
Ain't nobody, no matter what they might be thinking.
任何人都不可以
Sorry, honey.
對不起 親愛的
Things go loco around here every time I'm away.
每回我一離開 這裏就會出亂子
Remember the time at the big rodeo? Yeah.
還記得 那次牛仔競技比賽嗎?
Old Kale Beebe blew in higher than a kite...
老凱利來了 就是那個高個子
...slept on the sofa down there in Bick's office.
在你辦公室的沙發上睡著了
He must've rode nightmares all night.
那晚他一定在做惡夢
He cut the couch to ribbons with his spurs.
沙發都被他用馬鞭抽爛了
This here is Bick's room.
這是畢克的房間
This down here is your room, honey.
你的房間在樓下 親愛的
Ha, ha. - Ha, ha. Look, uh...
呃…
Luz, uh, we're married.
我們結婚了
Well, you know how that is.
你知道的
We, uh...
我們 額
We'll take these two connecting rooms here.
我們要住一間套房那裏
Make that into a sitting room where we can sort of sit and talk...
我們想把那間房作為起居室 坐在那兒聊天
...where the breeze can get at us.
還可享受陣陣微風
Howdy. - Oh.
你好
Petra's got your breakfast ready.
佩特拉把早餐准備好了
You and Jordan have had breakfast already?
你和喬丹都用過早餐了?
Sure, Bick and me, we have our coffee and talk every morning of our lives at 5:00.
每天早上五點 我們都會喝著咖啡聊天的
Trying to get things rounded up for the day.
把每天的事情都安排好
I thought I was going riding with him to the roundup.
我還以為會和 他一起去驅趕畜群
It would have been too hot for you. I told him so.
天氣對於你來說太熱了 我也跟他說過
Petra, bring it in here.
佩特拉 把早餐拿過來
You gotta watch out for that sun. It's rough.
這裏的太陽很毒 你最好小心一點
Sit down.
坐吧
Your blood's too thin. That's the trouble with a lot of Easterners.
看你細皮嫩肉的 東方人就是麻煩
Thank you, Petra. Gracias. Gracias.
謝謝 佩特拉
Oh, I'm fine, Luz.
我很好 盧斯
I'm a lot tougher, perhaps, than you think I am.
或許我沒你想象中 那麼弱不經風
Me...
我…
...I never had a sick day in my life.
我一生中都沒生過病
Except when I got throwed and tromped on.
哪怕是從馬背摔下來
All you gotta do is take it easy.
你也不要太過緊張
This rich Texas air will fix you up.
我們會為你安排好一切的
And don't you worry none about being lonesome.
你也別擔心在這裏會寂寞
I'm gonna round up the neighbors.
我會把鄰居們都叫出來
You're gonna meet some folks. Yes, indeedy.
讓你跟他們見見面 是的
You're gonna meet some folks.
你會跟他們都見面的
This is Mr. and Mrs. Bale Clinch.
這是貝爾.克林夫婦
- Bick, it's about time. Howdy, Bale.
真有你的 畢克.您好
Howdy, ma'am. I'd like you to meet my wife, Adarene.
這是我妻子 阿德雷妮
I'm mighty pleased to meet you.
很高興見到你
- Howdy, Adarene. - Howdy, Bick.
- 你好 阿德雷妮 -你好 畢克
This is our Judge Whiteside.
這是懷特賽德
How do you do? We sure are proud to have you here.
你好嗎 本尼迪特太太? 很榮幸你到這兒來
Bick, congratulations.
畢克 恭喜你
- Might happy for you, boy. She sure is pretty. - I think so.
- 你真走運 夥計 她真的很漂亮 - 是的
- Eula Japes. - Glad to meet you, ma'am.
- 這是烏拉.傑佩斯  - 很高興見到你
Howdy. - Good to see you.
很高興見到你 畢克
- This is Miss Wortan. - Howdy, Leslie. I'm mighty happy to meet you.
- 這是沃頓小姐  - 你好 萊斯莉 很高興見到你
Howdy. Hello, Bick.
早上好 你好 畢克
And Fernie Clang. - Miss Leslie, we're so glad to have you with us.
這是菲尼.克林 歡迎你的到來
- You've really done well for yourself. - Thank you, Fernie.
- 你會生活得很愉快的 - 謝謝你 菲尼
Hey, Fernie.
嘿 菲尼
Leslie
萊斯莉
You're gonna meet the neighbor I told you about.
現在來見見 我跟你提到過的鄰居
My next-door neighbor?
我的鄰居
Only lives 50 miles from here, with all those cows?
就是住在五十公裏外 有很多牛群的那位?
Vashti.
瓦斯塔
I'd like you to meet my wife.
我想向你介紹我妻子
Hello, Vashti. So nice to meet you.
你好 瓦斯塔 很高興見到你
Jordan's told me so much about you.
喬丹跟我說了 很多關於你的事情
Mighty glad to know you, Mrs. Jordan Benedict.
很高興能認識你
I'm awfully glad we're neighbors. And I hope we'll be real close friends.
很高興我們成為鄰居 希望我們能成為好朋友
- Hi, Bick. Well, howdy, Pinky.
嗨 畢克 早上好 賓奇
Hello, Mrs. Benedict.
你好 本尼迪特太太
My name is Mort Snythe. They call me Pinky.
我叫莫特.辛 他們都叫我"賓奇"
- Bick. Yeah?
畢克 嗯?
You, Bick. Come here.
快過來
What do you want?
怎麼了
Excuse me, ma'am.
失陪了 夫人
- We'll be seeing you. All right.
-我們會來拜訪你的
- This will perk you up. Oh, thank you.
-這會讓你興奮的 萊斯莉小姐 -謝謝
Folks, I propose a toast to a daughter of old Maryland...
我想敬這位 老馬裏蘭的女兒…
...that's blooming into a citizen of the Lone Star State.
成為德州的一員
- To the bride. To the bride.
敬這位新娘!
- You all right, honey? - Oh, I'm fine, thank you.
你沒事吧? 別擔心 我沒事
There's more than one bride here today.
-今天在這兒的不只一位新娘
How's that, Vashti?
-何以見得 瓦斯塔?
Mort Snythe and I were married yesterday in Hermosa.
莫特和我昨天剛在 "赫莫沙"結婚了
Leave the boy alone. I want to kiss him.
我要親吻他!
- I guess that leaves only me. - Aw, Luz.
現在就只剩下我了
Why, everybody in the county knows you'd rather herd cattle than make love.
盧斯 大夥兒認為 你趕牲畜的功夫比做愛強!
Yeah, well, one thing you gotta say for cattle.
對於牲畜你們 要記住一件事
Boy, you put your brand on one of them, you're gonna know where it's at.
把你的記號烙在它們身上 這樣就不會丟了!
Come and get it!
快過來吃東西吧!
Or I'll throw it in the creek.
或者我要把它扔進溪裏
It's the best food you ever ate, honey.
這是你從未 吃過的最好的東西 親愛的
It's real Mexican barbacoa.
這是地道的墨西哥烤味
It's where we get the word "barbecue."
也就是我們所說的"燒烤"
What is that?
那是什麼?
Calf's head.
小牛的頭
We take it and wrap it in clean white cloth...
我們首先用白布把它包裹
...and then wrap it tight in canvas...
再用帆布包緊
...and put it down in a pit of hot mesquite coals.
然後放到坑裏用
It stays down there 18 hours, and boy, them brains are sure sweet.
炭火熏上18個小時 那些腦髓最美味的了!
How fascinating.
太棒了!
Honey, I don't think I'm really terribly hungry.
我現在並不餓
It must be the heat.
可能是天氣熱的原因
You call this hot?
這樣就叫熱嗎?
Wait till July.
七月那時才真正熱呢!
Eat it while it's hot.
趁熱吃吧!
What's the matter with her?
她怎麼了 畢克?
That's what I was afraid of.
這正是我擔心的!
Leslie?
萊斯莉!
Good morning, Luz.
早上好 盧斯
What you doing up?
你在這兒幹什麼?
Getting breakfast.
做早餐
Look, Luz.
嘿 盧斯
I think there's something that we should get in the clear and in the open.
我想有些事情 我們應該說清楚
I don't want to take your place. I want you to know that.
我並不想霸占你的地方 這點我想讓你知道
But I can't have you taking my place either.
但我也不想讓你霸占我的
I can't be just a guest in my husband's house.
我不想只作為 我丈夫家裏的一個客人
There you are. - Good morning, darling.
你在這兒呢 早上好 親愛的
- How do you feel? Fine.
-你感覺怎麼樣了? -很好
Ah, you look fine.
你氣色還不錯
I want everybody to know, no matter what happens around this ranch in the future...
我想讓大家都知道 無論以後發生什麼事情
...I am never going to faint again.
我都不會再暈倒了
Well...
好吧
...I'll never get the hang of you, Mrs. Benedict.
我也決不會再扶你了 本尼迪特太太
Horse like that, that cost you a lot of money...
這匹種馬你可是花了很多錢的
...I'd use for breeding.
我還要拿它來配種
I wouldn't let anybody ride him. I don't care if she's your wife or who she is.
我不想讓任何人騎它 即使是你妻子也不行
Bick, I'd see she rides a more gentle animal if I was you.
要是我就讓她 騎一匹溫順點的馬
She's gonna fall off and break her neck.
她會把脖子給摔斷的
That's Old Polo.
那是老保羅
He's head vaquero.
是牧牛人的頭兒
He's been here longer than any of us, I guess...
他比這兒的時間 比我們任何人都長
...since Grandpa Benedict's time.
我爺爺那時候 他一直就在這兒
Look at them, honey.
看啊 親愛的!
There's never been anything like them in this world, I can tell you.
我敢跟你說 世界上不會再看到這種景象了
Did you ever see such stock?
你見過如此多的牛群嗎?
- Are they all ours? Yeah.
它們都是我們的?
These and 49,000 others just like them.
這些和其它49 000頭牛 都是我們的
Granddaddy and his boys used to drive his longhorns...
我爺爺和他的夥計過去 把這些長角牛…
...right through here, all the way to Kansas.
一路從堪薩斯趕到了這裏
- Imagine. - Yeah.
想象一下 -是啊
Yeah, he was a pretty good old boy. I mean, he was tough too.
他很能幹.他也很強壯
My old man brought stock from Europe and bred them to the best we had.
我的祖輩從歐洲買來種馬 然後好好喂養它們
Look out, you loco...
小心!
This right here is the result, honey.
於是才有今天的這一切 親愛的
Look at them.
看啊
How you doing?
你怎麼了?
- Tired, huh? - Now, don't you worry about me.
累了嗎? 別為我擔心
I'm a tough Texan now.
我是個堅強的德州人
You know I love you, Tex.
我愛你
Hello, Luz.
你好 盧斯
Hi, everybody.
你們好
Jett, hold on a minute.
等一下 傑特
I want you to take Mrs. Benedict back in with you.
讓本尼迪特太太和你一起回去
- Honey, you go along with Jett. Honey, I'm fine, really.
和傑特回去 這裏太熱了 親愛的 我沒事 真的
There's no use overdoing it. Go along with Jett.
沒必要勉強自己 和傑特回去吧
Good morning, Jett.
早上好 傑特
You take it easy, Jett.
小心點 傑特
I don't want to chew on this, Bick...
本來我不想說的 畢克…
...but I think we'd better get it straight.
但我想最好還是說清楚的好
I run the house, don't I?
這家歸我管 對嗎?
Her house, her kitchen, her help.
她的房子 廚房 庸人
- She don't even speak Spanish. - Oh, they understand plenty English.
她甚至不會說西班牙語 庸人們遲早會懂得英語的
I know how to handle Mexicans.
我懂得怎樣跟墨西哥人打交道
Doing it all my life.
我一輩子都在做這個
They'd sit on their honkers all day...
他們就會整天喝得爛醉
- ...if I didn't keep after them. - All right, Luz. Cool off.
如果我不盯緊他們的話 好了 盧斯 冷靜點
Well, I thought we ought to talk without her around.
我們最好趁她 不在的時候好好談談
I just don't want to feel that you're setting up against me, Bick.
我不想有種被 你欺騙的感覺 畢克
Nobody is setting up against you, Luz.
沒人欺騙你 盧斯
That gal is my wife.
那女孩是我的妻子
And you're fair enough, I think...
我想你也是很公平的
...to try and get along with her.
好好跟她相處吧
All right, I...
好吧
I'll catch me up a horse and help push the stock along for a while.
我還是找匹馬來遛遛吧
- Maybe it'll make me feel better. - All right.
或許這樣會讓我好受些
If you gotta push something.
隨你怎麼遛好了
When I get enough, I'll ride on in.
我走累的時候 我會騎上去的
Why did you come to Texas?
你為何到德州來?
Well, I mean, seems like everybody else is trying to get away from here.
大夥兒都想著要離開這裏
Me, I'm gonna get out of here one of these days.
或許過幾天 我也要離開這裏了
This is my husband's land.
這是我丈夫的土地
This is his home.
這是他的家
Who gets ahold of this much land unless they took it off somebody else?
誰能有那麼多的土地? 除非他們是從別人那裏奪過來的
You're not exactly loyal to your employer, are you, Jett?
你對你的老板確實 很不忠誠 傑特
No, sir, I'm not complaining. I'm not complaining.
不 我並沒有抱怨
They bought this land long ago.
這塊土地是他們 很久前就買下來的
Benedicts.
本尼迪特家族
- They got it through purchase years ago. - They took it off a bunch of Mexicans.
-這是他們很多年之前買的 -從無知的墨西哥人那裏買的
Why, that's not true, Jett.
這不對
They bought and traded for Spanish land grants.
這土地是得到 西班牙允許後
Paid for it, all right.
才買下的
They paid 5 cents an acre.
他們是以 每畝5美分的價格買下的
I know my folks is here in Texas long enough to get rich too.
我的祖輩呆在 這裏也變得富有了
Except they just weren't so foxy.
只不過他們沒那麼狡猾罷了
Leave it on, boy. I'll ride him.
給我 我來騎它
Nobody ride him but the senora.
除了太太之外沒人騎得了它
Been riding what I want to here for 30 years.
我在馬背上已經三十多年了
He buck off Lopez.
它剛把洛佩斯摔下來
If he bucks me down, he won't be the first one that's done it.
它要能把我摔下來 它也不是第一匹把我摔下來的馬
I suppose you came out here to show me how to run things too.
我倒也想看看你有什麼能耐
Let's go.
走
Now, I'm not too awful bad now.
我現在並不很糟
I got a few friends.
我也有幾個朋友
Madama likes me.
瑪塔瑪也喜歡我
And old Bick, now even old Bick...
畢克 他也
...he likes me...
開始有點
...a little bit.
喜歡我了
Well, now, but they don't like me...
當然 他們並沒那麼
...quite enough...
喜歡我…
...to kind of divvy up what they got way too much of.
只不過是想 從中多得一點而已
You are an odd one, aren't you, Jett?
你真是個奇怪的人 傑特.
But I like you.
但我喜歡你
I like you too.
我也喜歡你
I guess you're about the best-looking gal we've seen around here in a long time.
你是我們在這裏 見過的最漂亮的女孩
I think...
也是我來這以後
...the prettiest one...
見過的
...I think I've seen down here.
最漂亮的女孩
Why, thank you, Jett.
謝謝你 傑特
That's a very nice compliment.
你可真會奉承
And I'm gonna tell my husband of that, with your approval.
可以的話 我想把這話告訴我丈夫
Oh, well, now, I...
不
I wouldn't do that. Well...
我不會再這樣說了
No, I...
不 我
No, I wouldn't do that.
我不會再說了
Beautiful Reata. Tsk.
美麗的"利塔"!
Them's your neighbors live there.
他們是你的鄰居
- Who? Them kids there.
那些小孩
Them's your ranch people.
都是你牧場工人的孩子
Them's Angel Obregon's kids.
他們是安吉爾的孩子
That's the man that met us at the train.
那人我們在火車旁遇見過
They're sure in good shape, ain't they? Whole bunch of them sick.
他們很"健康" 對嗎? 他們全都病了
- What's the matter with them? - I don't know, just sick.
他們到底怎麼了? 我不知道
Every one of them.
只是全都病了而已
Wait a minute. I want to get out here.
等等 我想出去
Well, I wouldn't do that if I was you.
換成是我不會那樣做的
Wait.
等等
You are the boss. And you know it too, don't you?
你是老板 你知道這事的 對嗎?
- May I come in? Enter.
我可以進來嗎?
I'm Mrs. Benedict.
我是本尼迪特太太
Perdoname...
我叫佩多納姆
...that I do not rise.
我無法起床
The baby is sick.
孩子病了
My milk is not good.
我的奶水不好
Poor darling.
親愛的
Have you seen a doctor?
你去看大夫了嗎?
Doctor...
大夫?
He is too far to come.
離這裏太遠了
Say, Miss Leslie? I think we better be getting on.
萊斯莉夫人 我們該走了
This baby is extremely ill.
這孩子病得很重
Well, you're not supposed to be in there. It's...
你不該到這兒來的
Try not to worry, Mrs. Obregon.
別擔心 歐布雷夫人
I'll be back soon.
我很快就回來
Old Bick's gonna blow a gasket.
畢克會生氣的
What is it?
怎麼了?
What's happened to him?
它怎麼了?
What's wrong?
發生什麼事了?
Where in the world have you been?
你到哪兒去了?
Good Lord, I've been looking for you too.
我一直在找你
What happened to her?
她怎麼了?
We stopped by the village.
我剛才經過了村子
What happened?
怎麼了?
Just awful.
太可怕了
I don't know. She was...
我也不知道 她
...riding War Winds.
騎著"戰風"出去
She got thrown or something.
或許是從馬背上摔下來了
What does the doctor say?
大夫怎麼說?
Bad.
情況很糟
She hit her head on a mesquite stump.
她的頭撞到了樹樁上
She's been riding since she was 6.
她六歲就開始騎馬
She could ride anything. And now this happens.
她可以騎任何馬 沒想到發生這種事
How is she?
她怎麼樣了?
She's in a state of shock.
她摔得很嚴重 非常嚴重
Very serious. Concussion, possible hemorrhage.
腦部受到震蕩 內出血了
I'm doing all I can do.
我已經盡力了
I called Dr. Borneholm, got him on the phone.
我已經給 伯內霍姆大夫打電話了
He ought to be along any minute now.
他很快就趕過來
Doctor?
醫生
If I only hadn't bought that horse.
要是我沒買那匹馬就好了
Don't blame yourself, Jordan.
別自責了 喬丹
If I hadn't, she'd be alive right now.
要是我沒買的話 她就不會死
Don't blame yourself.
別再自責了
This is a great misfortune...
這件事很不幸
...but no one's to blame.
但沒人該受到責怪
Yeah.
是啊
Things happen.
事情已經發生了
Dr. Walker? - Mrs. Benedict, this is Dr. Borneholm.
-本尼迪特太太 這是伯內霍姆大夫
How do you do?
-你好
Bick, I sure wish I could have made it for Luz.
我很希望能救活盧斯
Dr. Walker did everything he could, I assure you of that.
沃克大夫已經盡力了 這點我可以向你保證
I know. Thank you.
我知道 謝謝你
Dr. Walker, there's more for you to do, I'm afraid.
沃克大夫 恐怕還有些事情要你幫忙
Mrs. Obregon's baby is very sick.
歐布雷夫人的孩子 病得很重
His temperature must be at least 105.
他的體溫至少在105度
Will you stop by, please?
你可以去看一下嗎?
Mrs. Obregon?
歐布雷太太?
In the village.
就在村子那裏
Jett will take you.
傑特會帶你去的
I'll go with you myself, doctor.
我和你一起去吧 大夫
Leslie.
萊斯莉
What is this?
這怎麼回事?
He can't do that.
你不能這樣
He can't go there.
他不能到那兒去
He's our doctor.
他是我們的大夫
- Our doctor? - Yeah.
-我們的大夫 -是的
You mean the Benedicts' only?
你是說 只是本尼迪特家的大夫?
No, I mean...
不 我是說
...all of us.
我們所有人的大夫
He don't tend those people.
他不能給那些人看病
They...
他們
...have a way of doing things by themself.
能夠自己想辦法的
How'd she get there, Jett?
她怎麼到那兒去的?
Oh, don't go climbing onto me.
別又拿我開刀
I don't feel none too good about it.
我也不想這樣的
Jordan, darling, I don't think you quite understand.
喬丹 親愛的 我想你還不明白
There's a child who's very sick.
有個孩子病得很重
I must take Dr. Walker.
我必須帶沃克大夫去
You'll go, won't you, doctor?
你會去的 對嗎 大夫?
I'll be back just as soon as I can, darling.
我會盡快回來的
I'm a lot better, honey.
我現在好多了 親愛的
That's a good boy.
這就好
Where's my horse?
我的馬呢?
I shot him.
我向它開槍了
Bone was broken.
它的骨頭斷了
Somebody had to do it.
必須有人這樣做
Thought it'd be better if it was me.
我想最好還是由我來做吧
The baby?
孩子怎麼樣了?
Alive.
活下來了
Thanks to Dr. Walker.
多虧了沃特大夫
Good.
那就好
Bick.
畢克
Excuse me, but we've gotta have you in here for a few minutes, if you can break away.
我們這裏有些事情 想和你談談
Jordan.
喬丹
Say, Bick, you're sure holding up fine.
你很快就好挺過去的
It's times like this that folks really show what they're made of, and you're holding up fine.
這時刻才真正能 表現出一個人的堅強
- Mrs. Benedict, bye-bye. Oh, goodbye.
本尼迪特太太 再見
Vern and me thought a lot of Luz, Mrs. Benedict.
維恩和我會想念盧斯的
But I guess everybody did.
大夥兒都會想念她的
Yeah, at least everybody came.
至少大夥兒都來了
Biggest gathering for a funeral I ever saw in Texas.
這是我在德州 見過的最盛大的葬禮了
Mm. Shame Luz wasn't here to enjoy it.
只可惜盧斯沒能到場
Well, I mean, she always did like a big get-together and everything. Heh.
我是說 她一直都很喜歡盛大的聚會
She'd have had a fine time.
她該生活得很幸福的
- Well, bye. - Goodbye.
好 再見
- Come see us. - Thank you, bye-bye. Come see us.
-常來看我們 -謝謝你們 再見 常來看我們
Jordan...
喬丹
...I think you'll agree with me that your sister was a very generous woman.
你姐姐是一個 非常慷慨的人
She wanted that boy to have something...
她想給那個人 一些
...something worthwhile.
值錢的東西
Now that little piece of land is worth, oh, 5-... ...600 dollars at most.
也就是一小塊價值… 500到600美元的土地
I'm going to ask you, in reverence to the memory of Luz Benedict...
我想問你 出於對盧斯.本尼迪特的尊敬
...I'm going to ask you to give one Jett Rink...
你要給傑特.林克…
...a check for twice the value of that land.
一張相當於那塊 土地兩倍價值的支票
We can clean up the whole matter right now.
現在就開始著手這件事吧
Jett, come on inside. I want to talk to you.
進來 我有事情跟你說
Now, just a minute here, Bick.
等等 畢克
Afraid I'm gonna beat you to it.
恐怕這次我恕難從命了
I'm quitting.
我不幹了
I lost the one friend I had in this place, and I know it too.
在這兒我 已經失去了一個朋友
So I quit. I'm dead quit. Don't have to say another word to me.
我不幹了 你不必再跟我說什麼
Nobody's firing you, Jett.
沒人要解雇你
Boy, howdy, nobody's firing me.
是的 沒人要解雇我
I told you, I quit.
我告訴你 我不幹了!
Nobody wants to fire you.
沒人想解雇你
Now, just come on inside and listen to what we have to say.
進來跟我們商量一些事情
Come on in here, Jett. Come on in here, boy. Heh.
快進來 傑特
- Hi, Jett. Nice to see you. Hi.
傑特 很高興見到你
- Howdy. Good to see you. - Howdy.
-你好 傑特 很高興見到你 -你好 傑特
Have my seat here, boy. Sit right down. Sure looking good today.
請坐 夥計 你今天氣色很不錯啊
Sit down, Jett. Gonna tell you about a little piece of luck's come your way.
坐吧 我要告訴你 一件讓你興奮的事情
Sit down, young man, sit down and make yourself comfortable.
坐吧 年輕人 別拘謹
It's a real bad wind that doesn't blow somebody some good.
有的人是 好運擋也擋不住啊
Amen.
阿門
Jett, I don't guess I have to tell you... ...Luz was a woman of strong sentimental feeling.
盧斯是一個堅強 又很富有感情的人 這點我無需多說
She prepared a list of things that she wanted to give the people on Reata.
她把要送給"利塔" 所有人的東西都列出來了
Yes, we find that she wanted to... Heh. Well, that is...
是的 她想要給…
...we find that her bequest to you is in the nature of a little piece of ground.
她給你遺贈的是 這裏的一小塊土地
It's that little piece we used to call "Buffalo Wallow."
也就是"水牛壇" 那一小塊土地
Now...
現在
She wanted to give you something. I know she did.
她想給你東西 我也知道她會的
It's always been my aim to kind of keep Reata intact, within the family.
但保持"利塔"完整無缺 是我一向的目標
Now, that little piece is worth...
這塊土地的價值最多是…
...hmm, at the most... How much, Bale?
多少來著 貝爾?
At the most, 5- or 600 dollars, Bick.
最多是500到600美元 畢克
Yes, now, um, Mr. Benedict, wanting to honor his sister's wishes...
本尼迪特先生 遵從他姐姐的遺囑
...and, of course, right along with his own personal feeling for you...
當然 還有他對你的關愛…
...now, he wants to see to it that you get something really worthwhile.
他想讓你的付出 得到更多的回報
Well, now, to get right down to the point, Mr. Rink...
言歸正傳吧 林克先生
...we're prepared to place in your hands in cash...
我們准備 付給你現金…
...the sum of $1200.
1 200美元
- Yes, sir. Ha, ha. - Boy.
好的 先生 -孩子
Twelve hundred dollars...
1 200美元
...which any of these gentlemen here, I'm sure they'll be happy to tell you...
在座的各位先生都會 很高興地告訴你…
- ...it's twice the value of that land. Definitely. At least.
這相當於 那塊地的兩倍價錢
Twice the value of that land.
-沒錯 -至少是兩倍價格
That's a lot of money, Jett.
這可是一大筆錢
What are you aiming to do with all of it?
你拿著它要幹些什麼呢?
You're in the chips now, boy.
你現在有錢了 夥計
There it is. There it is, boy. Ha, ha.
快拿著吧
- And it's all yours. Ha, ha. Sure is.
這都是你的
I don't know what to say. Ha, ha.
我不知道該說些什麼
She was a fine lady.
她人真的是很好
Yes, she was a fine lady. Hallelujah.
是的 她人是很好 哈利路亞!
Amen.
阿門
And I...
我
I want to...
我想要
I want you to know that I appreciate her, uh, generosity.
我很感激她的這份慷慨
And yours too, Bick. And you all.
還有你 畢克 你們在座的各位
I sure do want to thank you for it.
我很感謝你們
You know something, Bick? Ahem.
你知道嗎.畢克?
I don't know, but what it just might not be...
我也不知道 但這或許…
...a pretty good idea to gamble along with old Madama.
這種做法或許 不是個好主意
How do you mean?
你是什麼意思?
Just gamble along.
自己碰碰運氣
Just keep what she give me.
留著她給我的東西
I'm sentimental too, Bick.
我也是有感情的 畢克
I just think that it's good to gamble along with her.
我想最好是留著這塊地
I know that land ain't worth much but then, someday...
我知道它不值幾個錢 但有一天
...I just might up and put my own fence around her.
我發展起來後 我就會用柵欄把它圍起來
Call her "Little Reata."
然後命名為"小利塔"
See you.
再見
There's only one thing more important than money, and that's land.
世上唯一比 金錢重要的東西就是土地
Why, I've heard Luz say it a thousand times.
盧斯已經說過上千遍了
Pa said it, and Bick Benedict says it. And it's true.
畢克也是這麼說的 是真的!
You ever get up to Deaf Smith, you come and pay us a visit.
你真該來我們 "史密斯牧場"看一看
We're just on the outside of Umbarger.
我們就在"安巴傑"的另一邊
Only a little bitty piece, only we had a run of luck.
那地值不了幾個錢 不過我們還算走運
Only? Well, a gusher come in last year.
-還算走運? 去年那裏可發現了一口油井
- How wonderful. - Right now it's bringing in a million.
-真是太好了 立刻就帶來了上百萬
- A million gallons? - Dollars.
-一百萬加侖? -美元
- A million dollars a year? - Million dollars a month.
一百萬美元一年?
- Oh, a month. - Goodbye.
一百萬美元一個月 -再見
- Thanks for treating us right. Thank you for coming.
感謝您的款待 -感謝你們的到來
I just love talking to you, Uncle Bawley.
我很喜歡和你聊天 保萊叔叔
Now that it's over, you get that fellow of yours to take you around and show you our country.
以後 你可以讓你的丈夫… 帶你去看看我們的國家
See San Antonio... ...Dallas and Houston.
看看聖安東尼奧 達拉斯 還有休斯頓
I'm so impatient. I want to see it all right now.
我都等不及了 我現在就想去看看
You don't have to hurry, honey.
不必那麼心急 親愛的
It'll be here when you get around to it.
你會有時間去看的
Been here a long time.
時間長著呢
And once you see it all, and have lived with it as I have...
當你看完之後 然後像我一樣 在這裏再生活上…
...well, let's say 25 years from now, you'll feel about Texas just like I do.
二十五年 你就會和我一樣了解德州了
- Twenty-five years from now. - Mm-hm.
再過上二十五年!
Twenty-five years from now, I'll be almost 50.
二十五年之後 我就五十歲了
It's a nice age, Leslie.
這可是一個黃金年齡 萊斯莉
You'll see wonderful things in Texas when you're 50.
你五十歲的時候 會看到很多奇妙的事情
Perhaps.
或許吧
But I won't care as much then.
但那時或許 我沒那麼在乎了
You will care more.
你會在乎的
- Because then... Hey, Bawley. you'll have been part of it all.
因為那時 你已經成為了它的一部分
- Come on, we need you in the powwow. Coming.
快過來 大夥兒都在等著你呢
Judge, how's it shaping up?
法官 這是怎麼回事
It's gonna be all right.
一切都會好起來的
You get with it, Gomez.
格梅斯 把你的人都叫走
Get your people out. I don't want them sitting on their honkers come election day.
我可不想在大選日那天 看見他們醉醺醺的坐在那裏
Everything will be bueno, senora. It will be the same, good.
一切都會安排妥當的 先生
Goodbye, Gomez.
再見 格梅斯
I love you.
我愛你
Well...
額
...thank you.
謝謝
We're just talking business. Just business.
我們在談生意而已
Oh, please don't mind me.
別在意我
Do go on.
你們繼續
I'll listen quiet as a little old mouse.
我會像一個 小老鼠一樣靜靜地聽的
You'd be bored, honey.
親愛的 你會無聊的
This is dull.
這很無聊的
Why, I'd be fascinated.
怎麼 我對這個很感興趣
Leslie, we're talking about politics.
我們在談論政治
You married me in Washington, remember, darling?
親愛的 我們是在 華盛頓結婚的 還記得嗎?
I lived next door to politics, brought up with it.
我可是在政治的 熏陶之下成長的
Please do go on talking. I'd love it.
請繼續吧 我喜歡聽
This is men's stuff.
這是男人的事情
Leslie, how about a cup of coffee or a drink or something?
萊斯莉 來喝杯咖啡或者茶怎麼樣?
Men's stuff.
男人的事情!
Lord have mercy.
上帝真是仁慈!
Set up my spinning wheel, girls. I'll join the harem section in a minute.
你們快過來 我倒要聽聽他們說的是什麼政治
Now, Leslie.
聽著 萊斯莉
Don't you go worrying your pretty little head about politics. Heh, heh.
漂亮的小姐是 不必關心政治的
You mean my pretty, empty head, don't you, judge?
你是指我漂亮而無知 對嗎 法官?
Could I get the coffee for you, Leslie?
我給你來杯咖啡好嗎?
You too, Uncle Brutus?
你也是這意思嗎 布魯特叔叔?
You don't feel well, Leslie.
或許你身體不舒服 萊斯莉
I feel just great.
我感覺很好!
My adrenaline glands are pumping beautifully.
我的感覺一切良好
If I may say so before retiring...
在走之前我想說的是…
...you gentlemen date back 100,000 years.
你們又回到了十萬年前
You ought to be wearing leopard skins and carrying clubs.
你們應該穿著獵豹皮 拿著大棍子
Politics.
政治!
Business.
生意!
What is so masculine...
這個所謂的
...about a conversation that a woman can't enter into it?
男人間的 談話到底是什麼?
Leslie, you're tired.
萊斯莉 你累了
Perhaps I am.
我或許是累了
Judge, I think if you get down in Brewster county and campaign...
法官 我覺得如果你沿布魯斯特村走下去
Yeah, well...
額 好吧
Pinky, I reckon I'll go on upstairs and get my beauty sleep.
我想我該上樓睡覺去了
You go ahead on, honey.
去吧 親愛的
Good night, gentlemen.
晚安 先生們
Good night, honey. - Good night, Vashti.
晚安 親愛的 -晚安 維斯泰
Good night, Vashti.
晚安 維斯泰
That's right, send the children on up to bed...
這下好了 把孩子們打發去睡覺
...so the grown-ups can talk.
這樣大人就可以談話了
- Good night, Leslie. - Night, honey.
晚安 萊斯莉 -晚安 親愛的
Oh, I must've dropped off.
我一定是太累了
Oh, darling, I am sorry about my caveman speech.
親愛的 我為剛才 "石器時代的發言"道歉
I'll apologize to the others first thing, I promise.
明天一大早我 就向其他人道歉
That's big of you.
你真夠大膽的
- You certainly distinguished yourself. - Shh. They can hear.
今晚你可真的是出盡風頭了
Hear? They heard you already. Every word you said out there.
-他們會聽見的 -聽見?你的話他們都聽到了
We date back 100,000 years.
你在那裏說的每一句話 我們又回到了十萬年前
I said I was sorry about the name-calling.
我都為這件事向你道歉了
It was very impolite, I know.
我也知道 這樣很無禮
But in principle, I was absolutely right.
但從原則上講 我是正確的
You come down here and you try to tell us how to run things...
你來告訴我們做事的原則
...insulting my friends and everything.
讓我的朋友臉上無光
Now, you look here, Leslie.
聽著 萊斯莉
You're my wife. Mrs. Jordan Benedict.
你是我妻子 是喬丹.本尼迪特太太
I'm asking you, when are you gonna settle down and behave like everybody else?
我問你 你何時才能 像其他女人一樣守規矩呢?
Never. - Who do you think you are?
-永遠也不! -你以為自己是誰?
Joan of Arc or something?!
是聖女貞德嗎?
Jordan, where are you going?
喬丹 你要上哪兒去?
Jordan, take off your hat.
喬丹 把帽子摘下來
Carrying on like Carrie Nation, preaching stuff that's none of your business.
你真是愚蠢之極 談論政治不是你們的事情
Fixing the world. Why don't you join a club?
你為何不去參加俱樂部?
Honestly, Jordan. You make me sound just awful.
喬丹 你不能這樣對我
I'm not all that bad.
我還不至於那麼糟
You knew what a frightful girl I was when you married me.
你娶我的時候就知道 我是個很強的女孩
I did not deceive you, sir.
我沒有欺騙你
Why, from the very first moment, I couldn't have been more unpleasant.
自始自終 我就沒給人不好的感覺
Anyway, you're stuck with me.
再說 你也離不開我
Yeah, I guess.
我想是的
Honey, take your hat off.
親愛的 把帽子摘掉吧
Besides, you love me very much.
而且… 你深愛著我
Yeah.
是啊
But that fine mind of yours gets pretty repulsive at times.
在火車上的時候
That's not what you told me on the train.
你可不是這樣對我說的
Now you're gonna throw that up to me.
現在你又想來責怪我
I thought what we...
我還以為…
I thought what we said on the train was in confidence.
我們在火車上 說的話只有我們知道
Well, of course, darling.
當然 親愛的
But I'll never forget a single word you said to me.
但我永遠不會忘記 你對我說的每一句話的
You know, you can be pretty wonderful at times.
有時候 你可以做得更好的
Come on, partner.
來吧 寶貝
Why don't you kick off your spurs?
為何不把鞋子脫掉?
What a glorious, gorgeous, brand-new day.
真是美麗而嶄新的一天!
Let's spend every hour of it just you and I.
享受這每一刻吧 就你和我
Oh, honey, I'm beat.
親愛的 我很累
Why?
怎麼了?
Today you have all the good things in the world...
世上所有 美好的東西你都擁有了
...and a woman who loves you very, very much.
還有一個 深愛著你的女人
I know, but... That arguing takes a lot out of me.
但昨晚那次爭吵 讓我很難受
Oh, that was just frightful.
那真是太可怕了
Best part about quarreling is the making up.
爭吵最好的療法 就是彌補
When we make up, we make up too, don't we, honey?
我們一起來彌補 好嗎 親愛的?
Why can't we take a trip, really see Texas? Just let somebody else run Reata.
我們為何不去好好看看德州? 讓別人來管理"利塔"好了
- Hmm? - Oh, couldn't we?
可以嗎?
Honey, I want you to understand this:
親愛的 你要明白一點
I run Reata at all times.
"利塔"一直都由我來管理
- Of course, Jordan. - And that's the way it is.
曆來都是這樣子
Everything that's in it and on it is run by me.
這裏所有的一切 都是由我拍板
- Jordan, don't raise your voice. - That's the way it's always been too.
別那麼大聲 一直都是這樣的
Everything that has a Reata brand on it is run by me.
所有和"利塔" 有關的事情都由我管理
Does that include me?
也包括我嗎?
That's the way my father ran this outfit and the way my grandfather ran it, all of it.
我的父親和祖父 也都是這樣管理的
He kept it together for his son and my father kept it together for his.
他把一切留給了兒子 我父親也把這一切留給了我
And I'm keeping it together for mine.
我也會把這一切留給我兒子
- All 500,000 square miles? - All of it, for my son.
所有595 000平方公裏的土地? 所有這一切 都是我兒子的
You could at least say "our son."
至少你應該說"我們的兒子"
Our son.
我們的兒子
Don't you think that might be just a bit too much for one little baby?
你不覺得這對於 一個小孩來說太多了嗎?
Heh. Not if he's a Benedict.
只要是本尼迪特的 孩子就不算多
Well, better hope this is a boy.
你最好希望這是個男孩
Our baby.
我們的孩子
I just said I'm hoping it's a boy.
我只是說我希望是個男孩
What do you mean?
你是什麼意思?
I mean, why didn't you tell me?
為何不告訴我?
I'm telling you now.
我現在告訴你了
Well, honey why didn't you tell me?
為何不告訴我?
I mean, well, I should've known.
我該知道的
- You sure? - Sure.
-真的嗎? -當然
And our baby is going to be a boy, Jordan. I know it.
我們的孩子會是個男孩  我知道的
A boy very much like his father.
他會非常地像他父親
In many ways...
在許多方面都像…
...but not all.
但不是全部
Shouldn't she be putting on weight, honey?
她是不是有點輕了?
Well, it's natural, I think, darling, for him to be gaining faster.
我想 他倒是長得有點快了
Let me see.
讓我看看
They are heavy.
真沉
Hello, sweetheart.
你好啊 寶貝
Well, he's building up fine.
他長得可真快
"I am now stronger than ever...
"我現在比以前更堅強了"
...and am helping a young Dr. Guerra get started here.
"我在幫助年輕的 吉拉大夫在這裏工作"
Most every day I find myself walking three or four miles...
"每天我都要走上 三到四英裏的路程"
...to the dusty and dirty street of Vientecito Village.
"來回穿梭與'文特希' 村子的髒亂街道當中"
Hello, Angel. How are you?
安吉爾 你好嗎?
I'd like to speak to Mr. Gomez, the boss, the man that runs this place.
我想找戈麥斯先生談談 就是管理這地方的人
Mrs. Benedict, what is it I can do?
本尼迪特太太 找我有事嗎?
Mr. Gomez, I'm going to leave Dr. Guerra here with you.
戈麥斯先生 我讓吉拉大夫住在你這裏
He'll tell you a number of things that must be done.
他會告訴你 一些繼續著手做的事情的
This place is a scandal.
這地方真的是太髒了
Thank you, Dr. Guerra. I'll get in touch with you.
謝謝你 吉拉大夫 我會和你保持聯系的
Hello, Jett.
你好 傑特
- Howdy, Miss Leslie. - How are you?
-你好 萊斯莉小姐 -你好嗎?
I'm doing pretty good.
我很好
- You made some improvements. - Do you like it?
-看來你過得還不錯 -你喜歡嗎?
Looks good.
這裏真不錯
Well, it ain't much yet, but it's coming right along.
這裏雖沒那麼好 但畢竟有所改善了
- You know, I wouldn't have believed it. - Believed what?
我真不敢相信 相信什麼?
Truthfully, I wouldn't have expected this sort of talent to be one of your virtues.
說實在的 我當初 真沒想到你本事還挺大的
That's the first time I was ever accused of having any of that.
當初我可是被人 看成是一無是處的
It really is nice, Jett.
這裏真的很不錯 傑特
Real nice.
真不錯
Someday I want to have a place no one will be ashamed of.
有一天… 我這裏會讓所有人都羨慕
Oh, I cut them out of the newspaper. I thought they'd dress the place up a little bit.
這是我在報紙上剪下來的 我想這或許能讓 光禿禿的牆壁好看一點
Sweet of you.
你真可愛
Want to come on in here and sit down?
出來坐在這裏歇一會兒好嗎?
- Rest a minute? - Thank you.
休息一會兒 -謝謝
Having kids seems to agree with you, you know it?
有了孩子你顯得更快樂了
You're looking prettier than ever.
你看起來比以前更漂亮了
Just as good, anyway.
反正就是好
My goodness. And tea.
天啊 是茶!
- You like tea? - Of course, I love it.
你喜歡茶? -當然 我喜歡
Just seems down here everybody drinks gallons of coffee.
是的 這裏的人都是喝咖啡的
Yeah, I know it.
我知道
Mind if I pay you a rather personal compliment?
想聽我一句奉承的話嗎?
What is it?
什麼?
You make a very excellent cup of tea.
你泡的茶非常的棒
Yeah, well, I do a lot of things in a pinch.
必要時我可以做很多的事情
Would you like one lump or would you like two?
你想放一塊還是兩塊糖?
Well, I think I'll take mine straight.
我想就這樣喝
That's good enough for me.
看來我泡的茶還不錯
Oh. Boy. Ahem.
噢 孩子 啊哈
It's not too good, is it?
並沒有那麼好 對嗎?
When are you gonna get married, Jett?
你何時打算結婚呢 傑特?
Don't you need somebody to help you with this kind of responsibility?
你難道不需要人來 幫你打理這個地方嗎?
Well, when I get some time to look around, I'll go back East.
當我有時間到處去看看的話 我就會回到東部去…
To Maryland, places...
去馬裏蘭這樣的地方
Say, got any good-looking sisters back there might be interested in some poor people?
你還有長得漂亮 又樂意幫助窮人的妹妹嗎?
Money isn't all, you know, Jett.
金錢並非一切
Not when you got it. Heh.
你得到它之前就是全部
Jett...
傑特
...the other people around here, why don't they help themselves like you've done?
在這兒附近的其他人… 他們為何不能 像你一樣自助呢?
Well, now, ahem, when you say "other people," what do you mean?
你說的"其他人" 指的是誰?
Well, I've just come back from Vientecito.
我剛從"文特希"回來
Oh, that bunch of wetbacks.
就是那些"濕背"住的地方? （非法進入美國的墨西哥人）
Well, don't go getting me mixed up with none of them.
你不能把我和 他們混為一談
I'm just as much of Texas as Bick Benedict is.
我像畢克一樣 都是地道的德州人
- I'm no wetback. - Oh, I know that.
-我可不是"濕背" -我知道
You're like Jordan in that respect, attitude, everything.
在自尊心 態度 很多方面 你都很像喬丹
But your situation is so different. You're a workingman.
但你的處境不一樣 你是一個工人
Well, that's something I'm gonna try to fix.
我會做出一番成就的
Someday I will.
終有一天我會的
All right, Gomez.
好的 戈麥斯
Yeah, I understand.
我知道了
Yeah, thank you.
好的 謝謝你
Well, thanks for the tea party, Jett.
謝謝你泡的茶 傑特
And don't be such a stranger.
別老像個陌生人一樣
Stop by and pay us a visit.
路過的時候 常來看看我們
Well, I don't know about that.
我也不知道為什麼
Old Bick's still got his kettle on for me.
畢克還在為 我的事情耿耿於懷
Leslie?
萊斯莉
Hello, darling.
你好 親愛的
I was just having tea with Jett Rink.
我剛在傑特那兒喝完茶回來
- Gomez telephoned. - Oh?
戈麥斯打電話來說
"Mrs. Benedict comes to Vientecito. I hope you're not displeased," he said.
"本尼迪特太太到'文特希'去了" 他還說"希望你別生氣"
Look, I told you before... What about Jett Rink?
我早就告訴過你… 傑特怎麼了?
He made tea. Isn't that unbelievable?
他會泡茶 是不是難以致信?
He does so want to improve himself.
他真的想改善自己的生活
But your man Gomez, that camp he runs...
但那個戈麥斯 他去到那個…
It's hopeless.
真是無可救藥
You can't tear around this place with no regard for who you are, interfering with those people.
你要顧及自己的身份 別隨便去那個地方 和那些人糾纏在一塊
Jordan, that place is a scandal.
喬丹 那個地方很髒
- Dr. Guerra threw his hands up in horror. - That's his problem.
吉拉早就向你求助過的 那是他的問題
You've been a big powerful rich Texan for a hundred years. Do something.
一百年來你們都是有富有德州人 為何不做一些有意義的事情?
I'm not the Red Cross.
我可不是"紅十字會" 我只是個養牛人而已
If you won't, I will.
你不去做的話 我去好了
If you go near one of those dumps again, if you get mixed up in this migratory mess, why I'll...
如果你再去那種地方… 如果我再聽說你到那些地方去…
Just what will you do?  I'll leave you. That's what I'll do, I'll leave.
-那如何?         -我就休了你!
- Oh, there's my darling little girl. How are you, big boy?
我的寶貝女兒
Did you think your naughty mama was never gonna come up to see you?
你真以為你淘氣的媽媽 不會回來看你了嗎?
There's one thing you can be sure of.
有一點你必須清楚…
One of these days, I'm gonna run Jett out of this country.
這幾天我就勸說 傑特離開這裏
Who is it? Can you say hello to Luz?
快跟盧斯問好
Say, "Hello, Luz."
快說"你好 盧斯"
Lookit there. Lookit there. Say hello to little Luz.
快向小盧斯問好
I don't care what you say, Leslie, she does look like Luz.
不管你怎麼認為 親愛的 她真的很像盧斯
Oh, honey.
噢 親愛的
Y'all are gathered here on this fourth anniversary of my son's birth.
今天 我們來慶祝 我兒子四歲的生日
And your daughter's.
還有你的女兒
Well, of course.
哦 當然
I want to take this auspicious occasion...
我想借此良機跟大家說…
...to say that this young fellow right over here...
大家眼前的這個孩子
...is gonna grow up to be one of Reata's top hands.
將來長大後就會 成為"利塔"的主人
Hi, Daddy.
爸爸
I mean, this boy's gonna be the best.
這孩子會成為最出色的主人
He may even grow up to be better than his old man. Maybe.
或許有朝一日他 會比他的老爸更出色
Oh, girls, look at the pony.
孩子們 看那匹小馬
Come on, look at that.
它來了 兒子
There he is, son.
它是你的了
- He's all yours. - All mine, Daddy.
全是我的嗎 爸爸?
No!
不
Jordan...
喬丹
Take him around, Angel.
把它牽過來 安吉爾
- Take it easy, son. - Honey, he doesn't want to.
別緊張 兒子 他不想這樣
Oh, I rode before I could walk.
我會走路之前就學會了騎馬
But that was you. This is another person entirely.
但那是你 他和你不一樣
He's a Benedict.
他是本尼迪特家族的子孫
He's gonna stay on that saddle if I have to tie a hitch on him to keep him there.
要讓他學會在馬背上生活
Take him away.
把它牽走
Angel. No.
安吉爾 不行
Let him ride, Polo.
-不 -讓他騎吧 保羅
Let him ride.
讓他騎吧
Would you take him up for his nap? I think he's tired.
帶他回去睡午覺去 我想他也累了
Ho. There, now, that wasn't so bad, was it, son?
還不錯 是嗎 兒子?
Leslie...
萊斯莉
...Bick knows all there is to know about running a ranch. Bone, hide and hair.
畢克精通經營牧場的一切 這裏的一草一木
He don't know a dang thing about raising kids any more than his father did.
但他不懂得如何撫養孩子 比他父親好不了多少
So you just stay with it your way.
你要按照自己的方法
Help those children grow up to be what they want to be.
讓孩子們長大後做 他們自己想做的事情
I will, Uncle Bawley. I promise.
我會的 保萊叔叔 我保證
Well...
好的
...we're gonna hit the hay.
我們要睡覺去了
- Night, Leslie. Night.
-晚安 萊斯莉 -晚安
- Night, Bick. - Night, Pink.
-晚安 畢克 -晚安 平克
Good night, kids.
晚安 孩子們
Night, Vashti.
晚安 維斯泰
Well, I guess it's time for me to turn in.
我也該上床睡覺了
Night, Bick. Night, Bawley.
- 晚安 畢克 - 晚安 保萊
- Night, Leslie. - Good night, Uncle Bawley.
-晚安 畢克 -晚安 保萊
Good night, everybody. And don't forget to turn off the rain.
晚安 各位 別忘了把窗戶關上
Tired?
你累了嗎?
No.
沒有
Jordan...
喬丹…
What's happening is we're getting on each other's nerves.
我們或許在 一起生活得太久了
Could be.
或許吧
We've been together every day and every night since we first met each other.
自從我們第一次 見面我們就形影不離
Is that bad?
這不好嗎?
No.
沒有
Only we're getting in the habit of snapping at each other...
我們習慣了 彼此跟對方爭論
...on things we should have adjusted to years ago.
這些年來 這些我們都已習慣了
Jordan, I think it would be a good idea...
我想 讓孩子們回家
...if I took the children home for a visit.
看一趟或許會比較好
Home?
家?
Well, if you're homesick...
如果你想家的話…
I mean, if that's the way you want it.
我是說  如果你想回去的話
- That's not the way I want it, Jordan. - All right, then.
-這不是為了我 喬丹 -那好吧
It'll be better for us if we're apart for a while.
我們分別一段時間 對彼此都有好處
Better for us and the children.
對我們和孩子都有好處
It'll give us both a chance to think things out for a while.
這也給了我們 一個靜靜思考的機會
Gee, Les...
誒 萊斯
...I don't know. You know best, I guess.
我想你早就想清楚了
I think it will be best.
我覺得這樣最好了
Hi there. Morning.
-你們好         -早上好
Fine day for riding.
今天可是個騎馬的好日子
Oh, just magnificent.
簡直棒極了
See you later.
一會兒見
She's a lucky girl.
她是個幸運的女孩
If I had it to do it again, I'd still walk off with Jordan.
如果讓我重新選擇的話 我還是會和喬丹走的
Even if I knew it was gonna end like this.
即使我知道 結果會是這樣子
Leslie!
萊斯莉
You'll have no time to be homesick...
沒時間想念家了…
...with this wedding and Thanksgiving on us together.
和我們一起共度 這個婚禮和感恩節吧
Here, Pedro. Pedro, come here, Pedro.
"佩德魯" 快過來
Pedro, Pedro, Pedro.
佩德魯 佩德魯 佩德魯
Pedro, eat your dinner like a good boy.
"佩德魯" 快過來吃吧
Pedro, eat your dinner like a good boy, Pedro.
佩德魯 好好吃你的飯
Look at that.
看哪
Merciful Father, we bow our heads in gratitude on this, our Thanksgiving Day.
仁慈的上帝 值此感恩節 我們心懷無限感激
We give thee hearty and humble thanks for thy bounty...
對你的仁慈我們 表以衷心的感激
...beseeching thee to continue thy loving kindness to us...
願你繼續給予 我們這樣的仁慈
...that our land may still yield her increase...
讓我們的土地豐收
...to thy glory and our comfort. Amen.
讓你的仁慈之光普照大地 阿門
Pedro.
佩德魯
- That Pedro? - That Pedro?
那是"佩德魯"嗎?
Yes, darling. Yes. Mm-hm.
是的 寶貝
Oh, darling.
哦 親愛的
It's all right, baby.
沒事 孩子
No! No!
不
There, now, darling.
哦 親愛的
Oh, now, darlings.
It's a day when we're supposed to be happy.
今天是我們應該高興的日子
Come on, now, and smile...
好了 寶貝 笑一笑
...like Mommy.
像媽媽一樣
Something wrong, Miss Leslie?
怎麼了 萊斯莉小姐?
Now maybe you'll stop crying.
你們都該停止哭泣了
It's a message to you from your father.
這信是你爸爸寫來的
Is he gonna be here for dinner?
他要來這兒吃晚餐嗎?
Well, no.
不…
But he says:
但他說
"I hope my darlings are all very happy.
"希望我的寶貝們能玩得開心"
I want them to know I miss them very much...
"我想讓他們知道 我非常地想念他們
...and love each one very much."
非常地愛他們"
I could see you coming.
我看見你走過來了
Why, Mr. Benedict, this is a good surprise.
本尼迪特先生 這真是莫大的驚喜!
Hello, Jefferson.
你好 傑斐遜
We're having a wedding. Just plenty of excitement.
我們這裏正在舉行婚禮 大夥兒都高興極了
Dearly beloved...
"各位相愛的人"
...we are gathered together here in the sight of God and in the face of this company...
"今天 我們在這裏 謹代表上帝見證這一對新人"
...to join together this man and this woman in holy matrimony...
"見證這位男士和 這位女士的神聖結合"
...which is an honorable estate instituted of God.
"這也是上帝的榮耀和恩典"
David, wilt thou have this woman to thy wedded wife?
戴維 你願意娶這位女士為妻嗎?
To live together after God's ordinance in the holiest state of matrimony?
"在這神聖時刻 謹尊上帝的旨意而永遠相隨"
Wilt thou love her, comfort her, honor...
"你能終身愛她 尊敬她…"
...and keep her in sickness and in health...
"無論是健康或者疾病
...and forsaking all others...
都能放棄所有的一切…"
...keep thee only unto her so long as ye both shall live?
"在你們的有生之年 彼此常相廝守嗎?"
I will.
我願意
Lacey, wilt thou have this man to thy wedded husband...
"蕾茜 你願意嫁給 這位男士作為你的丈夫"
...to live together after God's ordinance in the holiest state of matrimony?
"在這神聖時刻 謹尊上帝的旨意而永遠相隨"
Wilt thou love him, comfort him, honor and keep him...
"你能終身愛她 尊敬他…"
...in sickness and in health, and forsaking all others...
"無論是健康或者疾病 都能放棄所有的一切…"
...keep thee only unto him so long as ye both shall live?
"在你們的有生之年 彼此常相廝守嗎?"
I will.
我願意
Bless, O Lord, this ring...
"祝福他們吧 上帝 這個戒指…"
...that he who gives it and she who wears it may abide in thy peace...
"他給她帶上的那一刻 就意味著他們永恒的結合"
...and continue in thy favor unto their life's end.
"彼此相愛 直到生命的終點"
Amen.
"阿門"
With this ring, I thee wed.
戴上這個戒指 你們就正式結婚了
Those whom God hath joined together...
"上帝祝福你們
...let no man put asunder.
永遠都不分開"
For as much as David and Lacey...
"戴維和蕾茜彼此同意
...have consented together in holy wedlock...
這一神聖的結合"
...I pronounce that they are man and wife.
我宣布 你們正式成為夫妻
Are you ready to come back to your old beat-up cowhand?
你准備回到 這個老牧牛工身邊嗎?
Jordan, I'm no different than I was when I left.
我和我離開時絲毫沒變
Well, we Texans like a little vinegar in our greens, honey. Gives them flavor.
我們德州人的活力 讓大草原別有一番風味
What do you think of old King Tut? - Boy, howdy. Some hunk of beef.
你們覺得這頭 "老牛王"怎麼樣? 夥計們 它身上的肉可真夠多的!
He's gonna make history too.
它也會成為曆史的
By the time Bick finishes his breeding program, he'll have an animal...
當畢克完成他的飼養計劃 他就會養出一頭…
...that's 99% beef and the rest exaggeration.
全身百分之九十九 都是肉的牛來
Say, Ollie...
歐利
...see that?
你看見了嗎?
That's Rink's truck. I don't want him hauling through my place anymore.
那是林克的卡車 我不想讓他在我的地方亂轉
Jett's got the easement, Bick.
傑特可以在 別人的土地上開車
He's got a right to go through the land. No two ways about that.
他有這個權利 這無可爭議
I'm sick and tired of his prospecting. I want him out.
我討厭他在這裏探礦 我想他立即離開這裏
He's borrowed about all he could. He's down to his last collar button, Bick.
他借來了所以能借來的東西 他現在真是窮得丁當響了
Sure is.
是的
Buy him out, Ollie. Buy him out, and get him out of here.
給他開個價 歐利 然後讓他趕緊滾蛋
Hello, Jett.
你好啊 傑特
What do you want?
你來幹嘛?
My well came in, Bick.
我的油井出油了 畢克
Fine.
好啊
Why, that's wonderful, Jett.
太好了 傑特
Everybody thought I had a duster.
大夥兒都以為我 那口井不會出油
You all thought Spindletop and Burk Burnett was all the oil there was.
你們都以為只有 "史賓雷特"和"貝克伯納"有油井
Well, I'm here to tell you it ain't.
我是來告訴你們 其實不是的 這裏也有油井
It's here. And there ain't a dang thing you gonna do about it.
還有一件讓 你們羨慕的事情
My well came in big, so big.
我的油井很大
And there's more down there, and there's bigger wells.
這地下還有 更多更大的油井
I'm rich, Bick!
我有錢了 畢克!
I'm a rich one.
我是個有錢人了
I'm a rich boy.
I'll have more money than you ever thought you could have.
我會比你有更多 你無法想象得到的錢
You and all the rest of you stinking sons of Benedicts.
比你和本尼迪特的 子孫都要有錢
Leslie, you go in the house. Take the women with you.
萊斯莉 帶上其他女士回到房間裏去
Jett, we're real glad you struck it.
傑特 我們很高興你挖出石油了
Now, you go on along home.
現在 你趕緊回家去吧
Oh, my, you sure do look pretty, Miss Leslie.
你真的很漂亮 萊斯莉小姐
You always did look pretty.
你一直都很漂亮
Just good enough to eat.
漂亮得… 讓人想咬上一口
Wait a minute, Bick. Wait a minute.
等等
Boy, take it easy, take it easy.
冷靜點!
Wait a minute.
等一下
My, you're testy, Bick.
你太暴躁了 畢克
You're testy as an old cook.
暴躁得像一個老廚子一樣
Bick...
畢克
...you should have shot him a long time ago. Now he's too rich to kill.
你早就該一槍把他崩了 現在他有錢 誰也動不了他了
You tell your client that Reata's my property...
跟你客戶說"利塔"是我的財產
...and the name of Reata's my property.
"利塔"這個名字也是我的財產
Texas courts are fair.
德州法庭會是公平的
He's to cease using the name of my ranch in his oil schemes.
用我牧場的名字來開油井 他一定會受懲罰
I won't have oil-digging on Reata, and I won't stand for its name being used.
在"利塔"農場我是不會鑽油井的 我也不能忍受"利塔" 這個名字被亂用
Is that clear?
明白了嗎?
Ma?
媽媽?
Mother!
They say Aunt Luz was in love with Jett Rink...
有人說盧斯阿姨 真的愛上傑特.林克了
...even if she was old enough to be his mother.
雖然她都老得 可以做人家媽媽
Now, Luz.
盧斯…
She was a character.
They say she was always trying to keep him from getting married.
她總是想阻止他結婚
He had to run off to marry you.
要娶你 他只能逃走了
What's that?
什麼?
Who said what?
誰說的?
Oh, somebody. I forget.
某人吧 我不記得是誰了
Heh. You know what they say?
知道他們是怎麼說的嗎?
They say that every girl in Texas was trying to catch Papa.
他們說 德州所有女孩 都想把爸爸釣上
They said, quote, that "there wasn't a prize bull like him...
他們說…我引用一句: "自從山姆.休斯頓成婚以後
...since Sam Houston got married."
就再沒這麼有魅力的男人了"
That's enough from her, Leslie.
她該閉嘴了
I'm sure it's quite true, darling.
親愛的 這在我聽起來完全真實
It took me two whole days to land him.
我花了兩整天時間才釣上他呢
Oh, really? It all sounds so fascinating and uncouth.
是嗎?
Where are you going?
你去哪?
Down the road to Smitty's for a Coke.
到樓下路口斯米梯 商店買可樂
With who? - Nobody.
跟誰去? 不跟誰
Stay home.
給我呆在家
Hey, you.
嘿 你!
Hello, Papa.
你好 爸爸
Howdy.
你好
- Where you been? - Down the road for a Coke.
你去哪兒了? 到樓下路口 那買可樂去了
With who? - Bob.
跟誰去的? 鮑勃
- Howdy, Mr. Benedict. Hello, Bob.
-你好 本尼迪特先生 -你好 鮑勃
Well, good night, Mr. Benedict.
嗯 晚安了 本尼迪特先生
Excuse me, Papa.
爸爸
Look, Papa, you busy now, Papa?
你現在忙嗎?
Never too busy for you, young fella.
年輕人 你有事 我怎麼忙都會理你
What's on your mind?
在想什麼呢?
Well, Daddy, it's like this.
爸爸 是這樣的
I am, Mama. I'm gonna be.
我…媽媽 我要…
I want to go to Harvard and then on to Columbia premed.
我要先去哈佛上學 然後去讀哥倫比亞醫學院預科
So you want to be a doctor?
這麼說來你想做醫生?
Yes, ma'am.
是
What about Reata, Jordy?
小喬丹 那"利塔"牧場怎麼辦呢?
He's counting on you to take over.
他可是指望你去接管"利塔"的
Yeah, I know he is. I know it.
我知道 我知道
But there's 50,000 guys can do it better than I can.
但這世上最起碼有五萬人 能比我在這一行做得更好
I don't want to live my life pushing cows around.
我不想以後一生 就在"利塔"牧場牧牛
Oh, Mama, I'd die for Papa if I had to.
如果為爸爸而死 我不會猶豫
Your father doesn't want you to die for him. He wants you to live for him.
你爸爸並不想你為他而死 他要你為他活下去
Talk to her, will you, Daddy?
爸爸 你跟她說 好嗎?
Reason with her.
跟她講道理
- I don't want this pinned on me. - I'll take all the blame.
我可不想她怪罪於我 如果媽媽要怪責 我會承擔一切
You just sort of soften the blow a little bit.
你只要幫我先把 媽媽的氣降低一點就好
I'll talk to him myself.
我自己跟他說吧
You can sway him, Mama. I know you can.
媽媽 我相信你能勸服他的 你能
It's not gonna be easy, honey.
寶貝 這個可不是件容易的事
Well, maybe I can catch her at a weak moment.
也許我可以在 她松懈的時候勸服她
You can do it, Daddy. I know you can.
爸爸 我知道你能辦到的 你能的
Darling, I've been thinking...
親愛的 我在想些事兒…
Me too.
我也正在想著些事兒…
About the children.
是關於孩子們的
That's funny. Me too.
真巧 我也是
We must be getting old.
我們看來定必是老了
Speak for yourself.
你說說看你在想什麼?
I wonder if we'd love them enough to do what's really right for them.
我疑惑 按我們的法則為他們做些 正確的安排是否算真正愛他們
Why, sure.
為什麼這麼想?這是當然的啊
I hope so.
我也希望如此
I mean so we love them too much, perhaps.
我是說… 也許我們愛他們實在太深了
So much we keep from doing what's right for them.
深得我們為他們做了 太多對他們好的事情
Not me.
我可沒有
You don't have to worry about me.
你不用擔心我
It's always the mother.
問題總是出在母親一方
Theory is, she don't want her fledglings...
有個理論非常有理 因為母親總不希望雛鳥
...to leave her nest and try their own wings.
離開自己的巢穴 讓它們振翅高飛
All that sort of stuff.
就是這麼回事
You mean...
你是說…
...you'd be perfectly willing to sacrifice?
你會願意犧牲自己的利益 讓孩子們振翅高飛?
Yeah.
當然
I'd sacrifice for her. You know that.
我願意為她犧牲 你知道的
I'm not so sold...
我不是很贊同你
...on that girls' school in Switzerland you're stuck on.
堅持讓她念的那間… 瑞士的女子學校
Now, don't get your feathers up.
別立馬就開始發飆
Judy's not so crazy about that Switzerland stuff either.
茱迪自己也對 那學校沒什麼興趣
Of course she isn't. That's exactly why she needs to go.
她當然沒興趣 但正是因為這樣她才必須去
Well, I wouldn't push her.
我不會逼她的
She, uh...
她…
...wants to go to Texas Tech.
想上德州工學院
- That is a man's school. - Well, girls go too.
那是男子學校 但也有女生在那上學
It's got the best animal-husbandry course in the country, she says.
她說那裏有 全國最好的畜牧專業
She wants to be a rancher like her old man.
她想像他爸爸一樣當個農場主
Like Bob Dace.
像鮑勃一樣吧
She's just got a little schoolgirl crush on that hulking Bob Dace.
她只是為那醜陋不堪的 鮑勃著迷而已
Well, she's got her mind set on it.
反正她的心意 已經打死那上面了
That's what she wants.
那才是她想要的
And I, for one, am willing to sacrifice.
而我 就是打算為她犧牲的一個
Well...
好吧
What do you say?
你怎麼說?
It seems we've hatched an odd pair of fledglings, darling.
看來我們孵養的雛鳥 還真是夠特立獨行的
Yeah.
Brace yourself.
你聽清楚了
Jordy wants to be a doctor.
小喬丹想做醫生
- He wants what? - He wants to be a doctor. He's set on it.
他想做什麼? 他想做醫生 他絕對是打死主意在這上面
Over my dead body.
除非我死了吧
- You know what he's supposed to do. - Well, he's not.
你應該清楚他應該做什麼的 但他不幹
He'd die for you, but he's not going to live his life for you. And he's right.
他願意為你而死 但是他不應該為你過 自己不願意過的生活
He'll do as we've all done.
他必須按照我們為 他訂下的路子走下去
He wants to go to Harvard first and then to Columbia premed.
他想先上哈佛 然後讀哥倫比亞醫學院預科
You're pretty handy with those terms.
你對那些術語說得 還是挺琅琅上口的嗎
I can see who's been cooking this thing up.
我知道是誰在幕後搞鬼了
Of course...
當然了…
...this would mean a big sacrifice on your part.
這對你來說算是大犧牲了吧
Well...
好吧
...no matter where he goes to school...
我不管他去哪裏上學…
...he comes right back home and runs Reata.
反正他以後都要給 我回家接掌"利塔"
Well, I guess you were right about one thing, Jordan.
我看你有一件事是對的
Me?
我?
On one thing.
在一件事上
We are getting old.
我們越來越老了
Who? - We are, Jordan.
誰? 我們 喬丹
We're the older generation.
我們是老一輩了
Aren't we?
不是嗎?
Suddenly.
突然地
Yeah.
是的
I guess so.
可能是吧
"... until a well 1000 feet in depth has been drilled...
"…除非石油或天然氣
...unless oil or gas shall have been struck at a lesser depth."
不用挖那麼深就可以產出"
Is that Vashti Hake's ranch?
那是用於 維斯泰.海克的牧場的條約?
- Yes. - Heh.
是的
Good.
很好
- How about Reata? - No.
那"利塔"的呢? 沒有
That Benedict's a hard guy to crack.
本尼迪特是個頑固派
Let's just keep punching, boys.
那就繼續努力
Hey, you.
嘿 你
Hospital. What's he covering up now?
[傑特.林克向醫院捐獻]醫院! 他到底掩蓋些什麼呢?
That hombre's going to overstep the mark one of these days.
他可成為了 最近的風雲人物
Just give him enough rope.
給他足夠長的繩索
- Give him enough rope and he'll hang you. - Heh.
給他的繩索夠長 你就被他勒死了
I'll get it.
我來聽
Hello?
喂
Yes?
No, this is her daughter.
不 我是他女兒
You did?
是嗎?
Oh, you have to find that out for yourself.
你得自己找出來
Luz, take your social life on the other phone.
-要進行社交去用另一部電話 -是你的電話
It's for you. I think he's nice.
他好像挺好的
- Who's nice? Jett Rink.
-誰?         -傑特.林克
- I don't want to talk to him. - What will I tell him?
我不想和他通話 我怎麼跟他說?
Let me talk.
我來說吧 我來跟他說
I'll tell him.
我會跟他說
I'll talk to him.
還是我跟他通話吧
Hello?
喂?
You've heard from me before on this, Jett.
傑特 沒打這通電話之前 你已經收到我的消息了吧
Judge Whiteside told you, and I told you.
看來是懷特賽德跟你說的 現在我告訴你
This is a cattle ranch, not an oil field. That's the way it's gonna stay.
這是個牧場 不是油田 所以以後它還是牧場
About the most expensive call you ever made.
畢克 這看來是你接過的 最為"昂貴"的一通電話了
Cost you a billion dollars a year for the next 50 years.
接下來50年 這會讓 你每年付出10億美元的代價
Couldn't we have just one little itty-bitty oil well so I could get my own private phone?
我們能不能開一口小小的油井 然後我就能裝一部私人電話了
The Naval Secretary told a press conference...
報告羅斯福總統後 海軍大臣告知媒體…
...that the battleship Arizona and five other warships were lost...
亞曆桑那號戰艦和另外五艘戰
...in the Japanese air raid on the naval base at Pearl Harbor...
在兩星期前日本對 珍珠港空襲之中被擊毀
...a fortnight ago.
他報告說有目前已知…
He reported that 91 officers...
共有91名軍官以及
...and 2638 enlisted men were known dead.
2638名現役軍人死亡
Aside from the Arizona...
除亞利桑那外
That only makes me realize that I'm losing you.
這只會讓我覺得我在失去你
Round yon virgin mother and child
#聖光環繞聖母聖嬰#
Holy infant so tender and mild
#聖潔嬰孩純真可愛#
Sleep in heavenly peace
#盡享天賜安眠#
Jingle bells, jingle bells Jingle all the way
#叮叮當 叮叮當 鈴兒響叮當#
Oh, what fun it is to ride In a one-horse open sleigh, hey
#今晚滑雪多快樂 我們坐在雪橇上#
Jingle bells, jingle bells
#叮叮當 叮叮當 鈴兒響叮當#
- Here they are. - Hello.
他們來了 -你好
- Come on down. When did you two sneak in?
過來 你們兩個什麼時候溜進來的?
The honeymooners.
甜蜜小倆口
Running off and getting married like that.
茱迪 很快就會有蜜月可度了
Boy, you're gonna get it. You know Mom wanted a big wedding.
你知道你媽一向希望 你能有一個盛大婚禮
Now, that's not true, Luz.
盧斯 不是這樣的
Oh, darling.
哦 親愛的
Well, not quite true.
不是完全這樣
Come down here and face the jury.
過來對著陪審團
Come on down, darling.
過來 親愛的
Howdy. Merry Christmas.
早上好 聖誕快樂
See what your mama and papa brought you from Dallas.
看看爸爸媽媽給你從達拉斯帶來了什麼
Oh, lucky you! Isn't that beautiful?
哦 你真幸運 這很漂亮 對吧?
Oh, Judy. Look at that.
茱迪 看那兒
Thank you, Mother.
謝謝你 媽媽
Well.
好
We came for you to see Angel.
我們來是讓 大家見見安吉爾的
He's the first soldier from Reata.
他是"利塔" 農場出的第一名戰士
- Merry Christmas, Polo. Merry Christmas.
-保羅 聖誕快樂 -聖誕快樂
My. Isn't he a fine-looking soldier?
看這小戰士多麼英俊?
Oh, just a minute.
稍等一下
Merry Christmas, Angel.
安吉爾 聖誕快樂
Thank you.
謝謝
Today the wish of all of us is that the war ends quickly...
今天我們共同的祝願 是這場戰爭早日結束…
...and that you, Angel, return safely to Reata...
而你 安吉爾 能安全回到"利塔"來…
...and to all of those who love you very much.
敬所有深愛你的人
I'll drink a toast to that with anything in force.
我們幹杯
Come on now, and open it.
來 快 打開看看
- Hello, Dr. Guerra. - Hello, Dr. Benedict.
-你好 吉埃拉醫生 -你好 本尼迪特醫生
Just a little premature.
我還只是見習而已
Oh, I know, it takes time.
我知道這需要時間
- Oh, Jordan, this is Juana. - Hello.
喬丹 這位是胡安娜
She's been training out at the hospital.
正在醫院受培訓
Must be that darn north wind static or something. Ha, ha.
一定是因為吹北風了 這才產生的靜電
Don't tell me that you haven't learned that dry wind, friction and a heavy carpet...
你沒聽說過幹燥 摩擦 還有厚重的地毯…
...are not the only means of creating electricity between human beings.
並不只是兩人之間 產生靜電的唯一幾種方式?
How are you? Oh, Dr. Guerra.
你好啊 噢  吉埃拉醫生
- Thank you.
謝謝
Hey, Angel?
嗨 安吉爾
Can't you hang around and give me the lowdown on what it's like?
能不能留下跟我 說說軍中的一些情況?
- See y'all. - See you later, Pinky.
再見 -再見
Juana?
胡安娜
- Oh. Very nice meeting you. - Nice meeting you.
-很高興見到你 -我也很高興見到你
- Goodbye, Adios.
-再見 -再見
- Boys, let's get us some Christmas cheer. - You talked me into it.
-我們來為聖誕幹幾杯吧 -你說服我了
I'll go for that.
我要喝幾杯
I was afraid we were going to have a mighty dry Christmas.
朋友們 看來我們今年的 聖誕會過得非常不錯哦
I'm going to drink a toast to the two young men of Reata.
我現在要敬在 "利塔"的兩個年輕人
My two sons.
我兩個孩子
Jordy...
茱迪
...and Robert.
和羅伯特
Thank you, Mr. Benedict.
謝謝 本尼迪特先生
Better take it easy on the bourbon, Dad.
少喝點威士忌吧 爸爸
It's not good for you.
對你身體不好的
I'm not kidding you.
我不是和你開玩笑的
Certainly hate to see Angel go.
我不想見到安吉爾離開
That boy is the best dang man on the place.
那孩子是我們 這片地方最出色的男人
Now that you've finished college, it's time for you to take your place here...
現在是到你接管這裏 為我們的戰爭
...and produce beef for the war.
提供出糧食的時候
They need doctors, Dad. They need doctors in war too.
他們也需要醫生啊 爸爸 戰爭也需要醫生
I'm going to finish medical school if I can.
如果可以 我希望能完成醫學院的學習
You are being bullheaded.
你真是頑固得緊
I never would be any good running this place.
這片地方歸我管我 永遠也做不好的
Any man on Reata can do it better.
"利塔"中的任何人 都能比我做得好
Jordy, you're the one...
你是唯一的一人
...with a responsibility to Reata.
你是對"利塔"負 有責任的唯一一人
Your blood pressure's going up just while we're talking here.
我們在這裏交談時 你的血壓就升高了
Now, please, Papa, it isn't good for you. Just relax.
拜托 這對你沒好處的 放松點好不好
Don't you get fresh with me.
別以為我什麼都不懂
We're talking.
我們在交談呢
Yes, I heard.
我有聽到
It's Christmas morning.
現在可是聖誕節的淩晨
Isn't this something that could be discussed tomorrow?
你們明天再討論這些事情不行嗎?
There's nothing to discuss.
沒有什麼好討論的
When I come home, I'm gonna work with Dr. Guerra in Vientecito.
我回家後就會去"文塞塔" 醫院跟吉埃拉醫生一起工作
I love Texas as much as you do, Dad, and I want to work here.
我對德州的愛不少於你 我想在此地工作
I just want to work in a different way, that's all.
只不過我希望做的 是不同的工作罷了
Come on, Jordy.
別這樣 喬丹
Work with Guerra.
跟吉埃拉一起工作
Here's to you, Mr. Benedict.
這杯是敬你的 本尼迪特先生
You look beat, Mr. Benedict.
你看來好像不行了哦 本尼迪特先生
Here's to you. It's pretty good stuff.
敬你 這些酒非常棒
You make that yourself?
自己弄的嗎?
Make it every year.
是啊 我每年都弄的
My Christmas special.
我過聖誕節的特制品
No, sir, I mean the liquor.
我是說這些酒
Do you make the liquor yourself?
這些酒是你自己弄的嗎?
If you don't, it's about the only thing you don't produce on Reata yourself.
但如果不是的話 恐怕這是"利塔"牧場裏面 你唯一不自己弄的東西了
Say, boy.
過來坐下
Come over here and sit down. I got some serious talk to make with you.
我有些話想要認真和你談談
I've been watching you pretty close for a lot of years.
我跟你近距離接觸 也有很多年了
You're a ranchman.
你是名放牧人
And you're smart.
而且你很聰明
You're wondering why I'm talking to you.
你一定奇怪我 為什麼要跟你談
Bob Dace...
鮑勃…
...look me right in the eye.
看著我的眼睛
You could never be anything but a rancher. Could you?
除了放牧人 你還能成為其他別人嗎?
- No, sir. - That's my boy.
-不能 先生 -這才是我的乖孩子
But somebody else thinks I could.
但有別的人認為我可以
Not Judy. Not my Judy.
不是茱迪?
- No, sir, it's not Judy. - Who?
-不是 先生 不是茱迪 -誰?
President Roosevelt.
羅斯福總統
Listen to this.
聽聽這個:
"To Robert Haskell Dace:
"致羅伯特.哈斯科爾.戴斯"
Greetings from the president of the United States."
"來自美國總統的問候"
Let me see that.
讓我看看
"You are hereby notified to report...
"接此信後請於 12月28日前來報道"
...on December 28th, 5 a.m., for induction."
"淩晨五點進行 宣誓入伍儀式"
Well, it don't matter.
沒關系
Your draft board won't let you leave this place.
你的工作不會容許 你離開這片地方的
They'll make you stay. This is just as important as carrying a gun.
你的工作會讓你一直呆在這裏 這工作跟提槍上戰場一樣重要
I appreciate your confidence, sir, but...
非常感激您的厚愛 先生
Well, this is one thing that I'm not gonna try to get out of.
但這一回我不打算放棄
Fine. Heh.
好吧
Have it your way. You might as well.
隨你便 你跟其他人…
Everybody else does around here.
做的事情沒什麼兩樣
Well, I'll show you my heart's in the right place.
我會讓你看到 我的心擺的位置正確著呢
When you come back and this fracas is over with...
等戰後你回來… 管理這牧場的工作
...the job's yours.
就歸你管了
It'll be waiting for you.
我會等著你
I couldn't take it, sir.
我不能接受 先生
Papa, Bob and I have planned.
爸爸 鮑勃和我已有計劃
We want a place just our own.
我們需要一個二人的天地
You crazy kids, you.
你們這些小鬼 神經病了!
Can you imagine you'll ever have anything like this?
你們有想象過自己能 擁有像"利塔"這樣的財富嗎?
- Like Reata? - Gosh, no, sir. We just want a little place.
天哪 當然沒有 先生 我們只想要一小片天地就好
Just a little place, Daddy, that will allow us time for experimentation and progress.
小小的天地 可以給我們時間 去進行試驗 去進步
You see, sir, well, big stuff is old stuff now.
先生 你那些大事對我們來說 只不過是一些老人家的情感
"Big stuff is old stuff"?
大事不過是老人家的情感?
Daddy, Bob didn't mean to upset you.
鮑勃不是想頂你的 爸爸
He just wants to be honest, that's all.
他只是實話實說而已
We just want something little that's our own, that's all.
我們只想要一個屬於 我們自己的小天地 這就夠了
Just ours. You see, Dad?
只是屬於我們的小天地 你明白嗎 爸爸?
Yeah, honey. I see.
我懂了 寶貝
See you, Daddy.
再見 爸爸
Hey, Angel, come on.
嗨 安吉兒 聽著
Keeping it together all my life for them.
我為這片土地花了 自己一輩子時間
I battled in mesquite, dust, wind...
和灌木 塵土 風沙作斗爭…
...keeping it big.
使得這片牧場如此繁榮壯大
And for who?
但為誰呢?
I might just as well give it back to the dirt-eating Comanches.
最後還不是要 還給本地那些肮髒的土著
That's the Christmas spirit. Give it all back to the poor old Indians.
這就是這個 聖誕的精義所在了 爸爸 把這片土地還給 貧苦的印第安人吧
Don't tell me, I know.
不用跟我說 我知道
You're Jett Rink.
你是傑特.林克
- You're Judy? No, I'm Luz.
你是茱迪 不是 我是盧斯
Oh. Luz Benedict.
哦 盧斯 本尼迪特
Ha, ha. That I am. Come on in.
是我 進來
Dad's over at the bar.
爸爸在吧台那邊
Feel free, it's Christmas. Everybody gets one.
放松點 今天是聖誕 人人都有禮物的
Christmas?
聖誕?
I thought that was next week.
我還以為下星期才是呢
- Somebody ought to have told me about that. - Ha, ha.
其他人應該早點告訴我的
Christmas greetings from Mr. Jetexas himself.
傑特給自己的聖誕祝福
Hello, Bick.
你好 畢克
Sit down.
請坐吧
I guess Christmas is just about as good a day as any to talk a little business.
我看聖誕節也跟其他 談生意的時候沒什麼兩樣
Run along, Luz.
你先下去 盧斯
We got business to talk about.
我們有話要談
Bye, now.
先走了
Bye, Mr. Rink.
再見 林克先生
Everybody calls me Jett, honey.
小姐 人人都稱呼我傑特的
Bye-bye.
再見
What's on your mind?
你在想什麼?
The country needs petroleum.
國家需要石油
I'm going to Washington, Bick.
畢克 我准備要去華盛頓
The reason I'm going, and the reason I'm here, is oil.
我要去那的原因和我 來這的原因都是因為石油
I figured.
我看得出來
Want to talk a little business?
想談談生意嗎?
I'm ready.
隨時恭候
Seems like every time we made a deal, me and you...
似乎每次我們做生意的時候 我和你之間的…
...it just turned out pretty lucky...
結果總是非常幸運…
...for somebody.
對某些人而言
You know, all this oil around here hasn't made a lot of difference.
這附近的石油 也沒造成什麼不同
We live pretty much the way we always have here at Reata.
我們現在住的跟以前我們 住在"利塔"時候也差不多一樣
- Mm-hm. Just like we Benedicts found it. - Yeah.
就跟我們本尼迪特家族 開創這裏時一樣
Bick...
畢克
...Lord was good to you, setting that concrete pool right down in your own yard.
上帝待你真是不賴 直接就在你前院給你 安排了個遊泳池
Hey, come on in. Ha, ha.
下來啊
Oh, not now, Luz.
現在不行 盧斯
Well, it's good for the young folks.
對年輕人來說是好事
We'd have made improvements around here, oil or no oil.
不管有石油沒石油 我們在這裏已經取得了進步
Now, Bick, that 27.5 percent tax exemption on oil helped out some, didn't it?
但對石油進行27.5%稅收豁免 的確是有幫助的 對不對?
- Bale, I'll tell you what old Pinky thinks. - What?
貝利 我來告訴你 一些老人的愚見吧 願聞其詳?
That oil tax exemption is the best thing to hit Texas since we whupped Geronimo.
自從煙草之後 石油稅收豁免 是對德州沖擊最大的事物了
Yahoo!
呦吼!
One of the finest laws ever passed in Washington.
這是華盛頓 通過的最好的法案之一
All joking aside, Bick...
畢克 我不是開玩笑…
...Bale and I are not adverse to accepting a share of the credit for it.
這些事情我們有泰半功勞 這點我們不該拒絕接受
Not at all.
一點也不
How about an exemption for depreciation of first-class brains, senator?
參議員 有些以往的一流人物 如今逐漸老了 你何不也給 他們進行一番稅收豁免?
Whose? Yours?
誰?你?
My father's, for instance.
比如說我父親
He spent his life saving other people's lives.
他花了一生時間去拯救世人性命
How about some tax exemption there?
何不給他進行點稅收豁免
Leslie's always been real sharp-talking, hasn't she, Bick?
萊斯利說話一向一針見血 對吧?
Fair enough, judge. You've always been smooth enough for two.
非常正確 但你也一向能言善辯
Do you take each other for better or for worse...
"無論前路是好 是壞…"
...for richer or for poorer...
"無論是貧 是富…"
...in sickness and in health, until death?
"無論是疾 是康 你們願意執子之手 直到老逝嗎?"
Jordan Benedict...
"喬丹.本尼迪特
...wilt thou take Juana Villalobos, here present...
你願意接受…" "你身旁的胡安娜.韋拉波斯…"
...for your lawful wife...
"在教堂經曆聖母之儀式
...according to the rite of our holy mother, the Church?
讓她成為你合法的妻子嗎?"
I will.
我願意
Juana Villalobos...
"胡安娜.韋拉波斯
...wilt thou take Jordan Benedict, here present...
你願意接受…" "你身旁的喬丹.本尼迪特…"
...for your lawful husband...
"在教堂經曆聖母之儀式
...according to the rite of our holy mother, the Church?
讓他成為你合法的丈夫嗎?"
I will.
我願意
Join your hands and kneel down.
兩手緊握 雙膝下跪
Turn right back and then go along
The lady in the front and the gent follow along
Now you're home and now you swing Round and round with a pretty little thing
On the corner with the old left hand It's a right to your honey and a right, now round
Hurry up, Grandpa, can't you see You ain't as spry as you used to be
Barbed-wire gates and a great big date Promenade round or you're gonna get sprayed
Now the gals to the center and back to the bar And the gents to the center with a right-hand star
Now back to the left and not too far
Greet your honey, pass her by Pick up the next gal on the sly
Now the gals go in with a full turn round Like a jaybird walking on the frozen ground
Now the men go in with a full turn round Like a scared little rabbit chased by a hound
Spread that star way out wide Let's do-si-do on every side
Do-si-high and do-si-low Just turn around and here we go
Gals to the center and back to the bar The gents to the center with a right-hand star
Now back to the left and not too far
Greet your honey, pass her by Pick up the next gal on the sly
Now the gals go in with a full turn round Like a jaybird walking on the frozen ground
Yahoo!
#呦哈#
Now the men go in with a full turn round Like a scared little rabbit chased by a hound
Spread that star way out wide Let's do-si-do on every side
What did they say?
他們說什麼?
Gals to the center and back to the bar And the gents...
Friends and neighbors, uh...
朋友們 親鄰們…
...I want you all to meet my wife.
我給大家介紹一下我的妻子
- This is Mrs. Jordan Benedict III. Well, congratulations.
喬丹.本尼迪特三世太太
Congratulations.
恭喜!
He was the first Reata baby I ever saw.
"安吉爾今日靈柩歸故土"
I remember it as if it were yesterday when I picked him up.
他是我第一個 見到在"利塔"誕生的孩子 那就仿如昨天的事曆曆在目
He had a fever.
他當時發了燒
I didn't think he was going to live the day out.
我還以為他活不過那天了
On behalf of the United States Army...
我僅代表美國軍隊
...I am proud to present to you the flag of our nation...
給您自豪地獻上 我們國家的旗幟…
...which your son defended so gallantly.
您兒子在戰役中非常光榮 地所要拼力保護的旗幟
Oh, say, can you see
By the dawn's early light
What so proudly we hailed
At the twilight's last gleaming?
Whose broad stripes and bright stars
Through the perilous fight
O'er the ramparts we watched
Were so gallantly streaming?
And the rocket's red glare
The bombs bursting in air
Gave proof through the night
That our flag was still there
Oh, say does that star-spangled...
Everyone, just everyone in the world's gonna be there.
全世界所有人都會去那裏的
I'm gonna fly up to Dallas and I'm going to Neiman's.
我要飛去達拉斯 到妮夢瑪珂絲（著名服裝店）去
I'm gonna buy myself a sort of a starlight-white evening dress.
給自己買件光芒閃耀的夜禮服
Very plain and simple, and deadly.
簡單明了 但又漂亮不凡
Before you get so elaborately simple, you'd better hear what your father has to say.
在你作好 這些計劃之前… 你該先聽聽你父親的意見
We're certainly going. I promised Jett.
我們怎樣都要去的 我答應傑特了
Jett. What are you talking about?
傑特?你在說什麼?
He likes me. He likes my family too.
他喜歡我 也喜歡我的家人
He's always talking about you.
他一直談起你唉
My dear, darling Luz.
親愛的盧斯…
If I didn't know you had a Benedict head on those immature shoulders...
如果你不是還在 沒發育成熟的肩上 頂著顆本尼迪特家的頭
...I'd prescribe a good spanking.
我早把你狠狠揍一頓了
Oh, he's dreamy.
他好迷人
Ask the Snythe girls. Ask anyone.
你可以問問那些女孩 問所有人
He's just a rough diamond.
他是一塊待雕琢的玉
He's a rough rhinestone, and he's old enough to be your father.
是人造的玉而已 他老得都夠當你父親了
- What are you six evil men up to now? - Oh, honey.
你們這六個怪老頭在這幹嗎呢? 寶貝
It's a coronation. Old Jett's fixing to get himself crowned king.
我們這是在舉行加冕禮 傑特打算加冕成王了
Gotta have 10 million to be on the list.
最起碼要有1000萬美元 才可能出現在賓客名單裏面
All the most important people in the country will be there.
整個國家的重要人物都會出席
A coast-to-coast broadcast. Jett's gonna make a magnificent speech.
還會有現場直播 傑特要進行詞藻華麗的演說
I know. Ha, ha. I'm gonna write it for him.
我知道 我正准備為他寫這演說稿呢
It'll be heard across the nation by everyone.
全國上下都會聽到的
Eliminating one. - Yeah?
把一個人排除掉吧
- That's me. - Good.
就是我
Hooray!
萬歲
You stay away, you'll be the only folks in Texas who ain't there.
你們不參加的話看來 全加州也就你們沒去了
I suppose you're right. - You're roped in with the herd.
你們得合群點
You'll be dancing to Jett's fiddles just like all the rest of them.
跟我們穿上粉紅高跟鞋 像我們其他人般在傑特的 清幽小提琴伴奏下起舞
Well, if we go, then we'll do it right.
我們去便要形式正確
We're oil rich just like the rest of them...
我們是通過石油致富的 跟他們 其他人一樣
...so we'll go like the rest of them, only better.
所以我們前去也要 跟他們一樣 甚至更好
- Now you're talking like my father. The old Benedict spirit.
你現在說話倒像我父親了 這就是老一輩 本尼迪特的精神了
Set up one of your grand weekends.
你會過上幾個愉快的周末
Invite everybody. We'll take them down there with us.
我們要請完所有人 把他們都帶去
We'll show that so-and-so who's top people around this part of the country.
讓他們看看在 這片土地上誰更厲害
I'll even buy that four-engine Douglas.
我還要買一輛 四引擎的道格拉斯飛機
You can fly in some orchids from Hawaii.
你可以在夏威夷飛進花叢中
We'll load up our party, buzz in low on top of that building...
我們從酒店樓頂
...shake the tiles right off that hotel roof.
掀開磚頭飛進去
Oh, there's Lola Lane.
是洛拉.蓮
- I'll bet even Hollywood isn't so exciting. - Isn't it something?
我敢肯定即使是 好萊塢也沒這麼熱鬧
It's perfectly fabulous.
-真誇張啊? -太誇張了
Jett's always trying to do things bigger and spend more money than anybody else.
傑特總是要把自己的風頭 弄得無與倫比… 情願比別人出更多的錢
I can't wait to meet him. What does he do?
真的嗎?他是幹什麼的?
To some he's just a no-good so-and-so.
對一些人來說
Cars for the Benedict party.
他只是個盲目鑽探的傻瓜
There he is.
說曹操曹操就到
There's the emperor himself.
那個就是我們的"皇帝"了
Hey, isn't this terrific? Look at Luz. She's queen of the parade.
是不是很宏大?看盧斯 她居然是遊行隊伍中的皇後
You didn't tell me.
你沒跟我說過
You know about this, Leslie?
你知不知道這事 萊斯利?
No, I didn't.
不 不知道
Oh, Lord.
噢 天哪
My daughter, queen of Jett Rink Day. What is this?
我女兒居然是傑特.林克 遊行中的皇後 這算什麼?
I don't know, Jordan.
我不知道 喬丹
She's done things before I haven't gone along with, but this... She's never been sneaky.
她居然沒經過 我同意便私自下決定
It's not exactly sneaky, Jordan, appearing in a parade.
實在是太可惡了 在遊行中拋頭露臉 根本不是什麼可惡
Don't try to be funny.
別開玩笑了
I'm not. I'm just as upset as you are.
我沒開玩笑 我和你一樣煩呢
I just know that Luz is intelligent enough not to be imposed on by anyone.
但我相信盧斯夠聰明的 不會讓他或者其他任何人騙的
Give me the desk.
幫我接櫃台
This is Bick Benedict. Did my daughter Luz Benedict come in yet?
我是畢克本尼迪特 我女兒盧斯 本尼迪特回來了嗎?
Now, get this. As soon as she comes in, have her call me.
給我記下 她一進酒店就叫她給我電話
Say, Luz...
聽著 盧斯
You know what I think I'll do?
知道我會怎麼做嗎?
Hmm?
嗯?
I'm gonna keep it just like this.
我會這樣做
I'll keep all those people, send them home.
把所有人留下來 然後送他們回家
I'm not even gonna open up this place.
甚至根本不打算開發這地方
Some girls might like a hotel all to themselves.
有些女孩希罕住高級的酒店
Me, I like company, Jett. I like lots of people.
而我 我喜歡有人陪伴 傑特 我喜歡許多人聚集在一起
Well, all right. All right.
好啊
You want lots of people?
你想要許多人陪伴?
I don't see any problem there.
我不覺得有什麼問題
Honey...
親愛的
...if there's anything you want...
有什麼需要只管說出來
...you just say it and you've got it.
然後你就能得到了
All right, I'd like a Coke.
好啊 我要一杯可樂
Whew. Ha, ha.
呼 哈 哈
Oh, now, that's impossible. That's just impossible.
不 不可能 就這不可能
You know as well as I do, Cokes are taboo. All soft drinks.
你跟我一樣清楚 可樂是這裏的禁忌品 那些都是些軟飲料
You make the rules.
隨你便吧
I make the rules.
你喜歡事情按
You like things your own way, don't you, Jett?
你自己的意願發展?
Let me ask you something.
我來問你些事
Do you like things your way?
你喜歡事情按你所想發展嗎?
Not very many people have things their way, do they?
不是很多人可以隨心所欲的
I don't get them my way very often.
我也很多事不能隨心所欲
Nope.
不
And you won't either, until you get married...
你也不會 除非你結了婚…
...get your man to give you what you want when you want it.
讓你老頭子給你任何你想要的東西
So?
那麼…
So if I was you, I'd start thinking about getting married.
那麼如果我是你的話 我就會開始考慮結婚了
Well, that's an idea.
這主意很不錯
You looked like a queen in that parade today.
今天的遊行中 你看上去真像一個皇後
That was my job.
那是我的工作
It's just what you are...
事實上你就是一個皇後
...Luz Benedict Il.
盧斯本尼迪特二世
You know, you could be the head lady of this part of the whole country.
在整個國家的這片土地 你可以成為最令人矚目的小姐
If you wanted to. lf you married right. If you married the right man.
如果你想的話 如果你嫁對人的話
Hmm, that's a sweet idea.
真甜蜜的好主意
Why don't I just announce it tonight...
我今晚為什麼 不當眾宣布出來呢…
...all them thousands of people out there just sitting, listening?
讓那幾千人在下面傾聽?
The whole of Texas.
讓整個德州的人都聽到
Boy, wouldn't that blow the roof off?
會不會笑掉人家大牙?
Jett, tell me something.
傑特 告訴我
Hmm?
恩?
- Is this a proposal? - Does it sound like one?
你這算求婚嗎? 聽起來像求婚嗎?
Oh, after a fashion, but not quite.
勉強算 但不確實
What do you want me to say? You want me to say something you can laugh at?
你想我說出一些 會讓你大笑的話?
No.
不
What I wanted to say is I think you're a wonderful girl.
我只是認為 你是個迷人的女孩
And I do think you're beautiful, and I think...
而且你很美
You're fascinating to me, and I've always been looking...
我對你著迷 我一直在找尋一個…
...for a girl like you.
如你般的女孩
That sure would blow the roof off, wouldn't it?
是不是笑掉你大牙了?
Hey, you've got a long way to go tonight.
今晚還長著呢
Look, I'm very flattered. Any girl would be.
我受寵若驚了 所有女人都會這麼覺得
You be a good boy, now.
聽話 現在
I'll see you later.
我們遲些見
I hope the storm doesn't louse up your party, Mr. Rink.
希望這場風暴 沒破壞了你的派對
Slip-up, boy. I just forgot to order the right kind of weather.
是我疏忽 我忘了 "預定"一份正確的天氣了呢
I heard a twister hit Waco.
聽說有龍卷風
What's the matter? Can't you talk United States?
你怎麼回事? 你就不能說英語
You're talking to my wife.
你在跟我妻子說話啊
My name's Benedict, Jordan Benedict, if that means anything to you.
我是喬丹.本尼迪特 不知道你有沒有印象
Okay, Mr. Benedict. I was just following orders.
我只是遵照吩咐做
Mr. Rink said he'd have my neck if I let any wrong people in.
林克先生說如果我讓一些 不相幹的人進了 去他就扭掉我脖子
- Benedict. Jordan Benedict. - Registering, please.
本尼迪特家人住的都很近
You Benedicts are all close together. They've got the Coronado Suite.
他們住在科羅納多套房
You're in the Fernando Suite.
你住在菲蘭多套間
I'm a mess. I must go to the beauty parlor.
我看起來糟透了 我得去美容院做做美容
You run for it before they close.
趕緊去 趕在晚會結束之前回來
The grand opening of the Jett Rink Airport and Emperador Hotel...
傑特.林克機場和 帝國酒店的盛大開張…
...is the latest milestone in the dramatic life of this virile son of Texas.
是我們來自德州的這位充滿 粗獷魅力的小子戲劇人生的又一 個
Virile so-and-so.
雄起
Howdy, everybody.
各位好啊
Hi, Adarene.
你好 阿德雷妮
- About time you got here. - Where's Pinky, the old bat?
-你也該來了 -男孩們呢? "賓奇"在哪啊?那老頭
Fernando Suite for Mr. Benedict, please.
請接電話 是本尼迪特先生 所住的菲蘭多套間打來的
Beauty salon. - Can you take me?
這裏是美容院 你們能幫我做個美容嗎?
Yes, if you can come right along.
當然 只要你馬上下來
Ha, ha. Thank goodness. I'll be right in.
謝謝 我馬上過來
- Who's calling, please? - Mrs. Benedict.
-請問是誰打電話呢? -本尼迪特太太
- You come right along, Mrs. Benedict. - Ha, ha. Thank you.
快來吧 本尼迪特太太 謝謝
- Bawley. - Yo.
勃利 -來了
Keep everybody freshened up. We'll be with you quick.
先讓大家振奮起來 我們很快出來
We're anxious to see old Jett come out of that chute.
真期待突然見到老鬼傑特 從那件衣服上突然鑽出來
Why couldn't they ride with us the way other people's kids do?
為什麼他們不像其他人的孩子 一樣跟我們一起開車來?
No, Luz had to fly her own plane, and Jordy and Juana had to drive.
盧斯要坐自己的飛機 喬丹和胡安娜要開車前來
Thank you.
謝謝你
Anybody here?
有人嗎?
We're all booked up.
我們預約滿了
I just called. I'm Mrs. Benedict.
我剛剛打過電話來的 我是本尼迪特太太
I'm sorry, but we're busy.
對不起 但我們現在很忙
I wait a little.
那我稍等一下好了
They're driving. It takes time.
他們正在開車趕來了 這需要時間
Oh, I know it takes time, I know it.
我知道這需要時間
I made the trip myself 400 times.
這段路程我自己也開過400次
But don't worry about the children.
但別擔心孩子們
Their behavior is odd, but their manners are beautiful.
他們舉止雖異常 但他們的態度還是蠻好的
Now, listen here, boy. I've taken just about enough of this from you.
你給我聽著! 我受夠你了
I didn't want to come in the first place.
我當初根本不想來這裏的
I wouldn't be here unless you'd let them bully you into it.
要不是你被他們威逼利誘 一番就嚇壞了 我怎麼會來
Now, for heaven's sakes, let's make the best of it.
既然來了 就看在上帝份上 好好利用這段時間
If you'll cool down, go on shaving, and finish dressing, I'll go down with you.
冷靜點 繼續刮你的胡子 穿好衣服 我等下就和你一起下去
Otherwise, you can go alone.
要不然你就給 我自己一個人下去吧
You know, honey...
寶貝…
...you're awful cute when you get riled.
你發怒時的樣子 真是可愛極了
- Hello, Mr. Benedict. - Hello, Uncle Bawley.
你好 本尼迪特 -你好 勃利叔叔
Hey, Jordy.
嗨 喬丹
You better hurry on in there. Your ma and pa are sure having a battle. Whew.
快進去吧 你老爸老媽好像在開仗了
- Hello, honey. - Well, where have you been?
你好 寶貝 去了哪裏?
We got tied up in traffic in town.
交通堵塞 遲到了一會
- Where's Juana? - She's in the beauty parlor.
胡安娜呢? 她去了美容院
Here, darling. Hello, sweetheart. - Where's Lupe?
你好啊 小寶貝
He's all right. He just didn't get his nap.
沒事的 他只是沒有睡夠
How's my child, Grandpa Benedict?
我的孩子怎麼了?
Is that Judy crying?
是不是茱迪在哭啊?
Oh, I hope I'm not too late. - Not too, come right in.
希望我不算太遲 沒有 快進來
Yeah?
誰?
Oh, hello, Juana. Yeah, he's here.
你好啊 胡安娜
Jordy, it's for you.
他在 喬丹 找你的
Yes, dear?
什麼事 寶貝?
Well, you stay right there, honey. I'm coming right down.
在那裏等我 我馬上下來
Don't you folks wait on us. We'll catch up.
你們不用等我 我馬上回來
Son, you're way behind.
孩子 你來遲了好久
Howdy, everybody. Look who we found.
各位好 看看誰來了
Well, there you are.
你在這裏
We were getting worried.
我們都有點擔心了
Say, you'd better get dressed, Jett.
你最好快穿衣服了 傑特
Oh, yeah.
額 好的
You wanted me to go over the speech with you too.
你還要我跟你 一起過一遍演講的
Come on, we better hurry.
快啊 我們得趕緊了
Well, I'm sorry, but it happens to be Mr. Jett Rink's orders.
對不起 但這是 傑特.林克先生的吩咐
And I'm just working here.
我只是在這打份工而已
It's everybody's orders. Same all over town.
我們對所有人都得遵守這吩咐 全城一視同仁
The young lady should've gone to a place where they do her people.
這位小姐應該去那些 幫他們的同胞做美容的地方
Well, if it isn't the queen herself.
這不是我們的皇後嗎?
Hi. You having fun?
-還開心吧? -正在制造樂趣呢?
We're making out. How you doing?
-你好嗎?         -很好
Good. Where are they, Mom and Dad?
我爸爸媽媽呢?
Don't trifle with your luck.
別把你的運氣 視同兒戲哦（你可真有運哦）
There you are.
你來了
Oh, you want to talk to me, Dad?
爸爸 要和我說幾句嗎?
Yes, if you can spare me a few moments of your time, I'd like to talk to you.
小姐 如果你能給我幾分鍾的話 我想跟你談些問題
Oh, Dad, must we now? - Yes.
現在必須談嗎? 爸爸?
We must hurry if we're gonna be on time for the grand entrance.
喬丹 我們得趕快到前廳去了
Oh, Luz, darling, you look just beautiful.
盧斯 親愛的 你看起來美極了
Uncle Bawley, help me round everybody up.
能幫我帶大家出來嗎
I'm sorry I'm so late.
真抱歉遲到了那麼久
All right, people. Hyah, hyah, hyah!
好了 各位…
Hyah, hyah, hyah!
哈 哈 哈
Get along, there.
大家靜一靜
There's a clause here...
這兒有個條款
Did some of you boys change this?
你們有改動過嗎?
Lord, man, no. We haven't changed a single comma.
連標點符號都沒有改動過
Changes tend to throw you.
似乎你不喜歡我們更動
"Columbus discovered only the shell of this country.
哥倫布發現了 這個國家的外殼
- Agassiz came and discovered fossil... " - Yeah, yeah, yeah.
阿加西…
Members only.
僅限會員
Where's Rink?
林克呢?
He went that way.
他從那走了
Looks like I just come in for a root beer. Ha-ha-ha.
好像來這喝東西一樣
That, my friend, is a Texas rain.
朋友 德州的
Hey, Bick. What you doing sitting up there? Come on, sit at our table, boy.
你們在那坐著幹嗎?
the Texan said, "Paul Revere?
"你們聽說過保羅.李維爾沒有? "德州人說:"保羅.李維爾?"
Oh, yeah, ain't he the fella that had to ride for help?"
"噢 對了 不就是那個 策馬過來幫忙的家夥嗎?"
In just a few moments...
在幾分鍾之後
...Mr. Rink himself will be here at the microphone.
林克先生本人… 就會在麥克風前
Come on, let's go.
快 我們走
Jordy smashed up the beauty parlor.
喬丹正在到處找傑特.林克
- He's looking for. - What?
什麼?
Where we have our hair done.
緣起於我們做頭發那裏
Jordy's looking for Jett to fight him, says it was his orders.
喬丹要狠揍傑特 因為那是他主意
- Why? - Juana. The girl said they didn't take wetbacks.
由於胡安娜原因 美容院女孩說 他們不幫"濕背人"美容
... of our entire country. Thank you, Congressman Bale Clinch.
The eyes of Texas are upon you
You cannot get away
Do not think you can escape them
At night or early in the morn
The eyes of Texas are upon you
Till Gabriel blows his horn
Stay here, honey. I'll be right back.
在這等我 寶貝 我馬上回來
All the livelong day
The eyes of Texas are upon you
You cannot get away
Is this young Benedict? - You invited me down here to insult my wife.
你邀請我來就為了淩辱我的妻子?
And you're gonna answer for it.
你必須對此負責
Aren't you the one who married a squaw?
你不就是那個娶了 印第安女人做老婆的那個嗎?
What's the matter? Ain't you having a good time?
怎麼了 小子?在這不爽?
Get them up, Rink. Everybody knows you got this coming to you.
把拳頭舉起來 林克 人人都知道你應該受到這樣懲罰
- Jordy, no. - Get them up, Rink. Let go of me.
喬丹 不要!
You want it now, in front of everybody...
你是想在人前
...or you want to come outside?
還是去外面?
I don't care much...
我可不管是
...whether it's here or outside...
在這裏還是在外面…
...so long as I get one punch at that stuck-up face of yours.
只要我願意給你的臉一拳
Sit down, sit down.
坐下
Heh, heh. Governor, how are you this evening?
州長 今晚還好吧?
Fine.
好的
And now to introduce our guest of honor...
現在 我們來介紹 我們的榮譽嘉賓
...we hear from a man known from the rocky coast of Maine...
坐在我們這裏的…
...to the Golden Gate in California.
是自緬因州到加利 福尼亞州無人不識的…
Ladies and gentlemen...
女士們先生們 我們的…
...our own Senator Oliver Whiteside.
參議員奧利弗.懷特賽德
Mr. Toastmaster...
尊敬的宴會主持人...
...Governor North...
...州長
...ladies and gentlemen...
...女士們先生們
The eyes of the entire nation are on us tonight...
全國的的目光今晚都聚集在我們身上
...as we gather here to honor them...
今晚 我們聚在一起紀念那些...
Get them up.
舉起拳頭
You had this coming to you for a long time.
你早該受我幾拳了
Texas has been kind to Jett Rink...
德克薩斯對傑特·林克太寬容了...
...and is ever ready...
...時刻准備包庇他
You're gonna get what you gave my boy.
你怎麼揍我孩子 我就怎麼揍回你
Get them up. Get them up!
舉起拳頭 舉起拳頭!
proud, friendly...
…驕傲 友好…
...warm-hearted, successful.
熱心 成功
Yes, successful, I am sure...
沒錯 我相信必定成功…
...beyond his wildest dreams.
...超越最狂野的夢想
But Jett Rink has never lost the common touch.
...但是傑特·林克的民意支持度一直很高
You ain't even worth hitting.
你根本不值得我去揍
Jett, you want to know something true?
想知道一些真實的事嗎?
You're all through.
你早就什麼也不是了
... all old friends who have known him and loved him...
...所有了解他 愛過他的老朋友
...since boyhood.
從小就認識他
Dear friends...
朋友們
...I'm going to ask you to come with me tonight...
今晚 我們大家來…
...as I turn back the pages in my book of happy memories...
一起回顧 一些美好的回憶
...and I recall the first time I saw young Jett Rink.
我記得首次見到 年輕的傑特.林克的情形
- Where's the boy? He went upstairs.
-那孩子呢? -胡安娜扶他上樓了
Come on, let's get out of here.
我們走吧
I'll go get Luz. - Hurry up.
我去叫盧斯 快點
moves the sand of glorious...
帶走光輝...
Luz, we're leaving.
來 盧斯 我們走
- in his face shone that light... - Would you excuse me, please?
-能讓一下嗎?
that destiny always uses...
命運總是...
The years pass quickly, as the years have a way of doing.
光陰似箭… 這是光陰的習慣
And now I see Jett Rink as a young man...
如今我見到的傑特.林克…
... afraid of neither opposition nor hard work...
是一個既不害怕別人反對 也不懼怕辛勞工作的 傑特.林克…
...his eyes set on a far distant goal towards which he's ever working...
他目光遠大… 在工作中 計劃中 奮斗中…
...learning, striving.
一步步實現自己的目標
And now we come to Jett Rink, the man.
現在我們的 傑特.林克進來了
Texas has been kind to Jett Rink.
德州是給了 傑特.林克許多機遇的地方
And Jett, never forgetting this kindness...
傑特也從來沒有忘記 過德州給他的機遇…
...is ever ready to devote his resources...
他隨時願意 捐獻出自己的資源…
...to the greater glory of the state which reared him...
給這片培養了他的土地…
...and which, in turn, does honor to him tonight...
這片土地也回報 以他今晚的榮耀
...in this great gathering here present.
回報以各位如此聚集一堂
And now, my friends, here...
現在 在這裏的朋友們…
...and to the many thousands of you listening across the nation...
全國收聽著 廣播的千萬人民們…
...I have the privilege...
我非常榮幸…
...yes, I have the great honor...
榮幸之極給大家介紹
...to introduce a legend in his own time...
一個這個時代的傳奇…
...a great Texan...
一名偉大的德州人…
...an outstanding American...
傑出的美國人!
...yes, my friends, a man.
沒錯 朋友們 就是他!
I give to you Jett Rink.
我們有我們的傑特.林克!
All the livelong day
The eyes of Texas are upon you
You cannot get away
Do not think you can escape them
At night or early in the morn
The eyes of Texas are upon you
Well, you can count on me.
你可以信得過我的
All right, then. Goodbye.
好吧 再見
How bad?
情況有多壞?
It hit pretty hard in Vientecito.
"文塞塔"受到了 很嚴重的襲擊
Dr. Guerra set up an auxiliary hospital. He needs help. I better get down there.
吉埃拉醫生開設了 臨時輔助性的醫院 他需要幫忙 我得馬上過去
You'll make better time if you wait till first light and fly.
等到明早做第一班機吧 那會讓你時間充裕些
I don't relish the idea of spending the night under Jett's roof.
我討厭睡在 傑特的屋簷底下
Me too.
我也是
If it weren't for transporting this circus, we'd all hightail it out of here.
如果不是有約定 我們早就逃開了
I hope she don't let this upset her too much...
希望這不會令她太過不安
...this business tonight.
今晚的事…
It's just one of those things.
只是這些淩辱的其中之一
Best thing to do is forget about it.
最好的方式就是忘掉它
Yeah. Well, go ahead. You forget it.
對 忘掉它
Me, I'm gonna remember it.
但我一定要記住這事
Now, look, Jordy.
聽著 喬丹
Take it easy.
別緊張
We've had just about enough excitement around here for one night.
我們才住一晚受的 刺激就差不多夠了
- Yeah, I guess so. - Sure.
我猜是吧
You've always had a mind of your own, and you've always used it.
你一向都很有自己的主見 並且會充分實現自己的主見
Done things pretty near your own way.
你一直都是按自己的方式行事
You knew what you was doing when you married in that direction.
你那樣結婚的時候你應該 已經知曉自己在幹什麼
I told you myself the morning after you broke the news. Remember?
你那天早上給我說 那消息時我就告訴過你 記得嗎?
I told you then that I knew Juana was a mighty-fine little gal...
我告訴過你我知道胡安娜 是一個很好的女孩…
...but when you and she got married, you was asking for trouble. Remember?
但是娶她的話就意味著 自找麻煩 你記得嗎?
I told you that.
我跟你說過的
Lots of folks in this part of the country are pretty jumpy about that sort of thing.
這裏的許多人對 這種事都太神經質了
- Jett's only one of them. - I know those people.
傑特只是其中之一 我知道有這種人
Just leave them to heaven. We're doing fine.
我們以前也碰過這種事 但我們都處理得很好
Look, Papa, if I'm concerned, it has to do with the people that ought to know better.
我只擔心怎麼去對付 那些本來應該更了解我的人
Like my own father.
譬如我自己的父親
- Hmm? - Just the simple truth, that's you.
很簡單 就是你
That's the way you think.
你就是這麼想的
Oh, good Lord, I don't care about Jett Rink.
我才不管什麼傑特.林克
But you, Papa, that's different.
但是你 爸爸 那不同
Now, you look here, Jordy.
你給我聽著 喬丹!
You can't talk to me like that.
你不能這麼跟我說話!
Why, Lord, no man can.
誰都不能這麼跟我說話!
I'm a fair man, and I've been fair all my life, with everybody.
我一向是個公正的人 一輩子正直無私 對所有人都是
And you, my own son, can't sit there and tell me that I'm not a fair man.
你 我的孩子 你不能跟我 這麼說我不是個公正的人
Look, Jordy...
聽著 喬丹…
...there's ways of living and there's ways of doing things that folks abide by...
生活有種種方式 做事有種種方式…
...when they want to live right and happily in comfort with their own people.
有人就喜歡和 自己的同胞一起… 覺得這樣生活才算舒服 才開心
And I always say Juana's a mighty-fine little gal, but...
我一直都說胡安娜 是個好女孩 只是…
Don't sit there and prove what I say! I don't like to hear you do it.
別幹坐在那裏證明我說的話 我不想聽到你這麼說
Dang it, boy, you're not being fair.
你一點都不公正
When that ruckus started down there tonight, who went after Rink?
在那騷嚷時 是誰去跟林克挑戰了?
Your old man.
是你爸爸!
Who took him to count? Your old man.
-誰為你出頭?是你爸爸!
- And why? - Why? Because I...
-那為什麼要幫我出頭呢?
- Because of my wife? - Yes.
因為我妻子?
No. No, because your son...
-是的 -不是! 那是因為你兒子
...Jordan Benedict, descendant of the long, proud line of Reata...
喬丹.本尼迪特… "利塔"漫長而又 令你自豪的血統後代
...got knocked right flat on his back in front of all Texas. That's why.
因為他被當著整個德州狠狠 地被人羞辱了 這才是原因!
Now, look, Papa.
聽著 爸爸
Just forget it. Don't worry yourself about it.
算了吧 別擔心了
Look, Mama, I guess you made a big mistake...
媽媽 當你跟我們這些 好吵鬧的德州人鬧在了一起
...when you got yourself mixed up with us rowdy Texans.
你真是犯了個大錯
Well, I'm shocked at you, and I'm shocked at all of us.
你真讓我吃驚 你們所有人都太讓我吃驚了
I'm just so ashamed.
我真羞愧
I'll never be able to forget the sight of my brother barging into the grand ballroom...
我永遠不會忘記我哥哥 闖入豪華的前廳…
...disgracing us. Then my father had to make it a bigger brawl.
在我們朋友的面前 讓我們丟臉!而我的父親 隨後把這臉丟得更大
I don't know when I'll be able to face people.
我以後還怎麼見人啊?
Keep seeing Jett, you won't have to face me.
你繼續去見傑特的話 就不用再見我了
Children.
孩子們!
Well, how about that, anyway, Mama?
這樣怎樣 媽媽?
I haven't been asked.
一直沒人問我意見
It seems that my family just can't tolerate his success.
我們一家好像不能 容忍他的成功似的
- My darling Luz. - Well, tonight meant a lot to Jett.
親愛的 盧斯 今晚對傑特意味非凡
Really, I know.
我知道的
If I only knew how to apologize to him, I'd go to him now.
真不知該怎麼去跟他道歉 如果我知道的話我早去了
I can't face all those people.
但我不能再面對那些人
The party's over. They've all gone home.
派對早結束了 賓客們都回家了
All?
都?
He passed out like a light in front of the whole crowd.
他在大眾面前暈了過去
- Oh, no. - That's what we heard, Luz.
不! 盧斯 這是我們聽到的消息
Well, he must have been ill.
他一定是病了
Weak with shame or something.
或者是羞愧難當
He was plain drunk, if you'll forgive me.
也不祈求你能原諒 我直說吧 他純粹是喝醉了
I don't believe you.
我才不信你
Party broke up early, but not a minute too soon.
派對提前散場了 但也不算快
Give me Mr. Rink's penthouse, please. Luz Benedict.
給我接林克先生的閣樓
You are not going up there, Luz, if I have to sit on you.
你不許上去 即使是要我把你 關在這裏我也不許你上去
Well, it's important. Do you know where he is?
事情很緊要 你知道他在哪嗎?
Luz, it's not like you to make a fool of yourself.
盧斯 在人前表現 這麼愚蠢不像是你所為
I know where he is, honey.
我知道他在哪
Come along with your Uncle Bawley.
跟勃利叔叔一起來吧
All right, Luz.
好吧 盧斯
If you must go.
你真決定要走便走吧
I must.
我必須走
I've always held a strange power over your mother.
在你母親面前我不知怎麼的 總是有股神奇的力量
I'm sorry, Mother.
對不起 媽媽
What do you say, dollface?
你說什麼 老板?
About ready to come along with your old pal now?
要跟我一起走了嗎?
It's time we hit the hay.
是時候上去睡覺了
I give up.
算了 我放棄
- Can we go to work now? - Leave him alone.
我們能進去幹活了嗎? 別管他吧
He owns the place. Let him enjoy it.
這地方是他的 就讓他好好在這玩一下吧
Shut up!
閉嘴! 閉嘴!
Ladies and gents...
女士們 先生們
Ladies and gentlemen, distinguished guests.
各位尊貴的賓客…
I just want to count the blessings...
我在此祈禱…
...that this great domain has bestowed upon her humble son.
這片土地仍記得 他卑微的子民…
My friends...
朋友們…
...this is a man.
這就是一個成功的人!
Old Mother Texas.
故土德州!
What did she give to me?
她給了我什麼?
Not a goldarn thing.
什麼都沒有!
You gotta work and sweat and steal it from her.
你必須在這塊土地上辛勤工作 揮灑汗水 從她身上偷掠拐騙
But I got mine...
但我的一切都是
...right out of the ground.
從這土地上而來的
Poor Jett...
可憐的傑特…
...fighting for what is good.
為美好的事物奮斗
Lucky.
充當奴仆!
Lucky for Bick Benedict...
充當畢克本尼迪特的奴仆
...her husband.
她丈夫的奴仆
Poor Jett.
可憐的傑特
Poor, pretty Leslie.
可憐美麗的萊斯利
Pretty Leslie.
美麗的萊斯利…
Pretty Leslie, wonderful, beautiful girl-bride.
美麗的萊斯利 完美 美麗的新娘
Poor boy.
可憐的孩子
Rich...
富足的…
...rich Mrs. Benedict.
富足的本尼迪特先生
She's beautiful.
她好美麗
Lovely.
可愛
The woman a man wants.
那是個吸引男人的女人
The woman a man's gotta have too.
也是個男人都要追求的女人
Thank you, Uncle Bawley.
謝謝你 勃利叔叔
Governor.
州長…
You know what you can do.
你知道你能幹什麼嗎?
Down Mexico way
That's where I fell in love
When stars above came out
- Just as soon as it lands, I'm gonna sell it. - Good.
它一降落我就賣了它 很好
This is for me, boy. The simple life.
這才適合我 簡單的生活
No more of this highflying nonsense.
我不再要這些 飛得高高的廢物了
Say, Juana, how does a hamburger and a piece of pie sound to you?
胡安娜 覺得來一份漢堡包 和一片薄餅怎麼樣?
- Sounds very good. - A what?
聽起來惹人極了
No more of this highfalutin stuff.
我們不去什麼高級地方了
Let's stop in up here and have us some chicken.
就在這個普通的 汽車餐館吃些雞肉吧
Then we can eat it with our fingers.
可能好吃得連自己的 手指都會吞下去哦
- Over here, honey? Yeah.
過來 親愛的 好的
- Howdy, folks. Good afternoon.
夥計們 中午好
Howdy.
你好
Nice place you have here. Been intending to stop...
你們這地方不錯 我每次開車經過
- ...every time I drove by. - Thank you.
都想進來坐坐 謝謝
What do you recommend, landlord? How's fried chicken?
有什麼好介紹?炸雞怎樣?
Little Jordy wants ice cream, Grandpa.
小喬丹想吃冰激淩 爺爺
Grandpa.
爺爺?
Ice cream it shall be.
冰激淩嗎
Give the little fellow some ice cream.
那就給這小家夥 來份冰激淩吧
Ice cream? I thought that kid would want a tamale.
冰激淩? 我還以為他應該吃些 玉米面團包餡卷（墨西哥傳統食
All right, sweetheart, give them what they want.
他們點什麼給什麼
What do you say, Juana? It's all right, isn't it?
怎麼樣?這樣可以嗎?
- It's good. Yes, sirree.
很好
After all that fancy food and high living, this is the life.
吃慣了山珍海味 住慣了高樓豪宅 這才是生活啊
Hey, you.
嘿 你們幾個
Now, let's see, the big plane should be arriving in Benedict around 1:30.
飛機應該在一點半左右 就到達本尼迪特的了
You're in the wrong place, amigo.
你們來錯地方了
Come on, let's get out of here.
走 我們出去
Your money's no good here.
你的錢在這裏沒用
Come on, let's go.
走吧!
- You too. - Hold on a minute.
你們也是 等等
Yes? What do you want?
怎樣?有何指教?
Now, look here, Sarge.
大廚 聽著
I'd sure appreciate it if you were a little more polite to these people.
如果你對這些人能 客氣點我會非常感激的
Oh, you would, would you?
你會非常感激?
I'm Bick Benedict. Your neighbor, you might say.
我是畢克本尼迪特 你可以說我是你的鄰居
Does that give you special privileges?
叫這名字就有什麼特權嗎?
The name Benedict's meant something to people around here for a considerable time.
本尼迪特這名字對周圍的人 應該還是意味了一些東西的
That there papoose down there...
那邊那個土孩子…
...his name Benedict too?
名字也叫本尼迪特嗎?
Yeah, come to think of it.
是的 想想吧
It is.
沒錯
All right, forget I asked you.
當我沒問過吧
Just go back and sit down, and we ain't gonna have no trouble.
你回去坐好 我們誰都別惹麻煩
But this bunch here's gonna eat somewheres else.
但這幾個老土怪得 到別的地方去找東西吃
- All right, come on, let's go. You too. Sue me. - Take your hands off him.
好了 給我走吧 快 你們倆也是
Now, you're out of line, mister.
你這就不對了 先生
Poor Daddy.
可憐的爸爸
Just leave him alone!
把他一個人丟下了
Is that the best that old horse thief can do?
那大塊頭也就這能耐?
- He's feeling your mood. Simpatico, darling. - Hmm.
他覺察到你的心緒了 親愛的
There's a lot of clair de lune in both of you old fire-eaters.
你們倆都有 一肚子的火爆脾氣
You're both rather gentle creatures, you know.
但你們也都是 非常溫柔的生物
How awful.
真惡心!
Those kids. Look at them.
你看… 那倆孩子
Those kids, in their infinite wisdom...
孩子們有著無限的智慧
...are smarter than we are.
著實比你我還要聰明
They know I'm a disgrace and don't hesitate to say so, either.
他們知道我很丟人 而他們不會猶豫去表現出來
Sure, even the calf's got my number.
甚至是那頭小牛 都知道我丟人了
Well, I don't have to take it from a sheep.
小羊都知道也太丟人了吧
Now, Jordan.
好了 老喬丹!
Hello? Hello, Vashti.
你好啊 維斯泰
Oh, we're all fine.
我們很好
How'd you make it back?
你們回歸了嗎?
Good.
好
- They all made it back in one piece. - Jolly.
-回歸一體了 -朱莉
Well, all the guests have finally gone.
對啊 我們的賓客都消失了
- Thank goodness. - Thank goodness.
謝天謝地
But more have left than we bargained for.
但卻留下了更多東西處理
Luz has gone on to Hollywood with...
盧斯跟洛拉還是 什麼的去了好萊塢
...Lona or Lola or whatever her name was.
她決定去好萊塢 看看適不適合她
She decided she'd like to see how she liked Hollywood.
我們家還沒有過 電影明星呢
- No, we've never had one, not on this side. - Good lord, an actress.
是的 我們從來沒有過 這方面都沒有 -天哪 演員
Well, Vashti...
聽著 維斯泰
...all you can do is raise them.
你能做到的只是把他們帶大
You can't live their lives for them.
不能代他們過活
No. Judy and Bob are out looking at a ranch.
茱迪和鮑勃在 照看一家農場
A small one.
很小的一家農場
Yeah. Jordy and Juana are gonna move into Vientecito.
喬丹和胡安娜 打算搬進去文塞塔
And we, we're home minding the babies.
我們嗎 我們就在家照看小寶貝咯
Hey, Bick? - Huh?
嘿 畢克 -嗯?
The sun's going down over the yardarm.
太陽下山了
- When are you gonna open up the bar? - Anytime, go ahead.
什麼時候開張酒吧啊? 隨時 來吧
Just remember, one day, that bourbon's gonna kill you.
記住 總有一天這些 威士忌會把你幹掉
Okay. It'll be me or it.
好了 不知是我幹掉它 還是它幹掉我
One of us has gotta go.
我們總有一個要走
Oh, me?
恩 我?
I'm gonna stay right here.
我要留在這裏
It's coming on spring.
快到春天了
Roundup time is no time to be away from Reata.
放牧的季節我們怎能離開
Yes, dear. Mm-hm.
是的 親愛的
Okay.
好的
Bye-bye.
再見
Yeah, honey, everybody's on the move. Strays leaving the herd.
寶貝 每個人都在走動 甚至連河流都在 離開我們的牧群了
I suppose I wouldn't mind it too much...
如果你想收拾行李暫時回家
...if you wanted to go pack up and go back home for a spell.
我不會介意的
Home?
回家?
Where do you think I've been this last breathless quarter of a century?
你以為我累得氣喘籲籲的 四分之一世紀裏面 都呆在哪裏了啊?
Home.
家?
Look, boy, I belong here.
聽著 小子 我屬於這裏
You really want to know what's gotten my goat?
你真想知道為什麼 那頭羊會這樣叫?
What, honey?
什麼 親愛的?
My own grandson don't even look like one of us.
我們唯一的孫子 看起來也不大像我們
So help me, he looks like a little wetback.
他看起來真像個"濕背人"
- Jordan. - Well...
喬丹 -好吧
Little muchacho fires up, don't he?
小家夥生氣了?
Well, I'm sorry, Jordan Benedict IV.
對不起啊 喬丹.本尼迪特四世
There's times a man just has to be honest.
有時人總該老實一點
You know something, Leslie?
你知道嗎 萊斯利?
There's no use for kidding, either.
我不是開玩笑
I'm a failure.
我其實是個失敗者
Nothing just turned out like I'd planned.
沒有什麼是按照我 所想去實現的
I just... I just feel like my saddle's...
甚至連馬鞍我都
...turning right out from under me.
覺得會抽身離去了
Do want to know something, Jordan?
你想知道些事嗎?
I think you're great.
我認為你棒極了
Oh, don't ask me why. There are some things that are difficult to explain.
別問我為什麼 有些事情很難解釋
You know all that fine riding you used to do, and all that fancy roping...
你以前騎馬騎得很棒 用繩索出神入化…
...and all that glamour stuff you did to dazzle me?
還有一切一切讓 我簡直眼花繚亂的魔術
Oh, it was impressive.
的確是讓人印象深刻
But none of it ever made you quite as big a man to me...
但那些都不足以使你在 我心中成為一個偉大的人…
...as you were on the floor of Sarge's hamburger joint.
只有那天 你倒在了 那家餐館的地上 我倒覺得了
When you tumbled rearward and landed crashing...
當你往後倒下時…
...into that pile of dirty dishes...
把整盤肮髒的菜都扣翻時
...you were at last my hero.
你最終成為了 我心中的英雄
That's what you always wanted to be, you know.
而那是你一直想做的
Could be.
可能是吧
When we went into that place, before the fight started...
我們進去時 在那場打斗開始前…
Oh. Oh, what a fight. It was glorious.
真是一場美妙的打斗! 太棒了
Before we went into that place...
在我們進去前
...I was feeling like you are now.
我正有你現在的感覺
I was thinking to myself:
我在暗地裏想:
"Well, Jordan and I...
"嗯…"
...and all the others behind us have been failures."
喬丹 我 還有我們家族之前人  都是失敗者
And then it happened.
然後事情就發生了
You wound up on the floor, on your back...
你倒在了地上
...in the middle of the salad.
倒在了一盤色拉中間
And I said to myself:
我對自己說:
"Well, after a hundred years...
"嗯…"
...the Benedict family...
"經過100了年…"
...is a real big success."
"本尼迪特家族…" "終於贏得真正的成功了"
You want to know something, Leslie?
想知道些事嗎 萊斯利?
If I live to be 90...
如果我能活到90歲…
...I'm never gonna be able to figure you out.
即使到那時候 我也不會忘記你